<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40396401</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1551-6709</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>49</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cognitive science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cogn Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Turing Jest: Distributional Semantics and One-Line Jokes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70066</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70066</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/cogs.70066</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Humor is an essential aspect of human experience, yet surprisingly, little is known about how we recognize and understand humorous utterances. Most theories of humor emphasize the role of incongruity detection and resolution (e.g., frame-shifting), as well as cognitive capacities like Theory of Mind and pragmatic reasoning. In multiple preregistered experiments, we ask whether and to what extent exposure to purely linguistic input can account for the human ability to recognize one-line jokes and identify their entailments. We find that GPT-3, a large language model (LLM) trained on only language data, exhibits above-chance performance in tasks designed to test its ability to detect, appreciate, and comprehend jokes. In exploratory work, we also find above-chance performance in humor detection and comprehension in several open-source LLMs, such as Llama-3 and Mixtral. Although all LLMs tested fall short of human performance, both humans and LLMs show a tendency to misclassify nonjokes with surprising endings as jokes. Results suggest that LLMs are remarkably adept at some tasks involving one-line jokes, but reveal key limitations of distributional approaches to meaning.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Cognitive Science published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of Cognitive Science Society (CSS).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trott</LastName><ForeName>Sean</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cognitive Science, University of California, San Diego.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walker</LastName><ForeName>Drew E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cognitive Science, University of California, San Diego.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Samuel M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cognitive Science, University of California, San Diego.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coulson</LastName><ForeName>Seana</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cognitive Science, University of California, San Diego.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cogn Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7708195</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0364-0213</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Distributional semantics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Experimental pragmatics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Joke comprehension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Large language models</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Verbal humor</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40396401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cogs.70066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Annamoradnejad, I., &amp; Zoghi, G. (2020). Colbert: Using bert sentence embedding for humor detection. arXiv preprint arXiv:2004.12765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apter, M. J., &amp; Desselles, M. (2012). Disclosure humor and distortion humor: A reversal theory analysis. Humor, 25(4), 417&#x2013;435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atari, M., Xue, M. J., Park, P. S., Blasi, D., &amp; Henrich, J. (2023). Which humans? PsyArxiv.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attardo, S., Hempelmann, C. F., &amp; Maio, S. D. (2002). Script oppositions and logical mechanisms: Modeling incongruities and their resolutions.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attardo, S., &amp; Raskin, V. (1991). Script theory revis (it) ed: Joke similarity and joke representation model.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aykan, S., &amp; Nal&#xe7;ac&#x131;, E. (2018). Assessing theory of mind by humor: The humor comprehension and appreciation test (ToM&#x2010;HCAT). Frontiers in Psychology, 9, 1470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bender, E. M., &amp; Koller, A. (2020). Climbing towards NLU: On meaning, form, and understanding in the age of data. In Proceedings of the 58th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (pp. 5185&#x2013;5198).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bender, E. M., Gebru, T., McMillan&#x2010;Major, A., &amp; Shmitchell, S. (2021). On the dangers of stochastic parrots: Can language models be too big? In Proceedings of the 2021 ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability, and Transparency (pp. 610&#x2013;623).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergen, B., &amp; Binsted, K. (2015). Embodied grammar and humor. In G. Brone, K. Feyaerts, &amp; T. Veale (Eds.), Cognitive linguistics and humor research (pp. 49&#x2013;68). De Gruyter Mouton.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergen, B., &amp; Coulson, S. (2006). Frame&#x2010;shifting humor in simulation&#x2010;based language understanding. IEEE Intelligent Systems, 21(2), 59&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binz, M., &amp; Schulz, E. (2023). Using cognitive psychology to understand GPT&#x2010;3. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 120(6), e2218523120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bischetti, L., Ceccato, I., Lecce, S., Cavallini, E., &amp; Bambini, V. (2023). Pragmatics and theory of mind in older adults&#x2019; humor comprehension. Current Psychology, 42(19), 16191&#x2013;16207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, T., Mann, B., Ryder, N., Subbiah, M., Kaplan, J. D., Dhariwal, P., Neelakantan, A., Shyam, P., Sastry, G., Askell, A., Agarwal, S., Herbert&#x2010;Voss, A., Krueger, G., Henighan, T., Child, R., Ramesh, A., Ziegler, D., Wu, J., Winter, C., &amp; Amodei, D. (2020). Language models are few&#x2010;shot learners. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, 33, 1877&#x2013;1901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butzer, B., &amp; Kuiper, N. A. (2008). Humor use in romantic relationships: The effects of relationship satisfaction and pleasant versus conflict situations. Journal of Psychology, 142(3), 245&#x2013;260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caucheteux, C., &amp; King, J. R. (2022). Brains and algorithms partially converge in natural language processing. Communications Biology, 5(1), 134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatterjee, A., Renduchintala, H. S. V. N. S. K., Bhatia, S., &amp; Chakraborty, T. (2024). POSIX: A prompt sensitivity index for large language models. Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2024 (pp. 14550&#x2013;14565). https://doi.org/10.18653/v1/2024.findings&#x2010;emnlp.852</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y., Li, Z., Liang, J., Xiao, Y., Liu, B., &amp; Chen, Y. (2023, February). Can pre&#x2010;trained language models understand Chinese humor? In Proceedings of the Sixteenth ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining (pp. 465&#x2013;480).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi, M., Pei, J., Kumar, S., Shu, C., &amp; Jurgens, D. (2023). Do LLMs understand social knowledge? Evaluating the sociability of large language models with SocKET benchmark. arXiv preprint arXiv:2305.14938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christiano, P. F., Leike, J., Brown, T., Martic, M., Legg, S., &amp; Amodei, D. (2017). Deep reinforcement learning from human preferences. Advances in neural information processing systems, 30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coda&#x2010;Forno, J., Witte, K., Jagadish, A. K., Binz, M., Akata, Z., &amp; Schulz, E. (2023). Inducing anxiety in large language models increases exploration and bias. arXiv preprint arXiv:2304.11111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coser, R. L. (1960). Laughter among colleagues. Psychiatry, 23(1), 81&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coulson, S. (2001). Semantic leaps: Frame&#x2010;shifting and conceptual blending in meaning construction. New York: Cambridge University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coulson, S. (2005). What's so funny?: Cognitive semantics and jokes. Cognitive Psychopathology/Psicopatologia cognitive, 2(3), 67&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coulson, S. (2015). Frame&#x2010;shifting and frame semantics: Joke comprehension on the space structuring model. Cognitive linguistics and humor research. Berlin/Boston: Walter de Gruyter, 167&#x2013;190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coulson, S., &amp; Kutas, M. (2001). Getting it: Human event&#x2010;related brain response to jokes in good and poor comprehenders. Neuroscience Letters, 316(2), 71&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coulson, S., &amp; Lovett, C. (2004). Handedness, hemispheric asymmetries, and joke comprehension. Cognitive Brain Research, 19(3), 275&#x2013;288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coulson, S., Urbach, T. P., &amp; Kutas, M. (2006). Looking back: Joke comprehension and the space structuring model. Humor, 19(3), 229&#x2013;250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degen, J. (2015). Investigating the distribution of some (but not all) implicatures using corpora and web&#x2010;based methods. Semantics and Pragmatics, 8, 11&#x2013;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doogan, S., Ghosh, A., Chen, H., &amp; Veale, T. (2017, August). Idiom savant at semeval&#x2010;2017 task 7: Detection and interpretation of english puns. In Proceedings of the 11th international workshop on semantic evaluation (SemEval&#x2010;2017) (pp. 103&#x2013;108).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, Q., Li, L., Dai, D., Zheng, C., Wu, Z., Chang, B., Sun, X., Li, L., &amp; Sui, Z. (2022). A survey on in&#x2010;context learning. arXiv preprint arXiv:2301.00234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubey, A., Jauhri, A., Pandey, A., Kadian, A., Al&#x2010;Dahle, A., Letman, A., &#x2026; &amp; Ganapathy, R. (2024). The Llama 3 herd of models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2407.21783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunbar, R. I. M. (2004). Language, music, and laughter in evolutionary perspective. In Kimbrough Oller and Ulrike Griebel (Eds.), Evolution of communication systems (pp. 257).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freud, S. (1960). Jokes and their relation to the unconscious. WW Norton &amp; Company.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firth, J. R. (2013). Ethnographic analysis and language with reference to Malinowski's views. In Man and culture (pp. 93&#x2013;118). Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golchin, S., &amp; Surdeanu, M. (2023). Time travel in LLMs: Tracing data contamination in large language models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2308.08493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodkind, A., &amp; Bicknell, K. (2018). Predictive power of word surprisal for reading times is a linear function of language model quality. In Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Cognitive Modeling and Computational Linguistics (CMCL 2018) (pp. 10&#x2013;18).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagendorff, T. (2023). Machine psychology: Investigating emergent capabilities and behavior in large language models using psychological methods. arXiv preprint arXiv:2303.13988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris, Z. S. (1954). Distributional structure. Word, 10(2&#x2013;3), 146&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, H., Peng, N., &amp; Liang, P. (2019). Pun generation with surprise. arXiv preprint arXiv:1904.06828.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henrich, J., Heine, S. J., &amp; Norenzayan, A. (2010). The weirdest people in the world? Behavioral and Brain Sciences, 33(2&#x2013;3), 61&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hessel, J., Marasovi&#x107;, A., Hwang, J. D., Lee, L., Da, J., Zellers, R., &#x2026; &amp; Choi, Y. (2022). Do androids laugh at electric sheep? humor &#x201c;understanding&#x201d; benchmarks from the new yorker caption contest. arXiv preprint arXiv:2209.06293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howe, N. E. (2002). The origin of humor. Medical Hypotheses, 59(3), 252&#x2013;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, J., Floyd, S., Jouravlev, O., Fedorenko, E., &amp; Gibson, E. (2022). A fine&#x2010;grained comparison of pragmatic language understanding in humans and language models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2212.06801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, J., &amp; Levy, R. (2023). Prompting is not a substitute for probability measurements in large language models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2305.13264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, J., Levy, R., Degen, J., &amp; Schuster, S. (2023). Expectations over unspoken alternatives predict pragmatic inferences. arXiv preprint arXiv:2304.04758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janes, L. M., &amp; Olson, J. M. (2000). Jeer pressure: The behavioral effects of observing ridicule of others. Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin, 26(4), 474&#x2013;485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jentzsch, S., &amp; Kersting, K. (2023). ChatGPT is fun, but it is not funny! Humor is still challenging Large Language Models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2306.04563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, A. Q., Sablayrolles, A., Roux, A., Mensch, A., Savary, B., Bamford, C., &#x2026; &amp; Sayed, W. E. (2024). Mixtral of experts. arXiv preprint arXiv:2401.04088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing, X., Talekar, C., &amp; Taylor Rayz, J. (2018). Comparing Jokes with NLP: How Far Can Joke Vectors Take Us?. In Distributed, Ambient and Pervasive Interactions: Technologies and Contexts: 6th International Conference, DAPI 2018, Held as Part of HCI International 2018, Las Vegas, NV, USA, July 15&#x2013;20, 2018, Proceedings, Part II 6 (pp. 310&#x2013;326). Springer International Publishing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, C. R., Chang, T. A., Coulson, S., Michaelov, J. A., Trott, S., &amp; Bergen, B. (2022). Distributional semantics still can't account for affordances. In Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society (Vol. 44, No. 44).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, C. R., Trott, S., &amp; Bergen, B. (2023). EPITOME: Experimental Protocol Inventory for Theory Of Mind Evaluation. In First Workshop on Theory of Mind in Communicating Agents.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kao, J., Levy, R., &amp; Goodman, N. D. (2016). A computational model of linguistic humor in puns. Cognitive Science, 40(5), 1270&#x2013;1285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan, J., McCandlish, S., Henighan, T., Brown, T. B., Chess, B., Child, R., Gray, S., Radford, A., Wu, J., &amp; Amodei, D. (2020). Scaling laws for neural language models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2001.08361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koestler, A. (1964). The act of creation. New York: Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosinski, M. (2023). Theory of mind might have spontaneously emerged in large language models. Retrieved from https://arxiv.org/abs/2302.02083</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kugler, L., &amp; Kuhbandner, C. (2015). That's not funny!&#x2013;But it should be: Effects of humorous emotion regulation on emotional experience and memory. Frontiers in Psychology, 6, 1296. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2015.01296</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuribayashi, T., Oseki, Y., Ito, T., Yoshida, R., Asahara, M., &amp; Inui, K. (2021). Lower perplexity is not always human&#x2010;like. arXiv preprint arXiv:2106.01229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauer, R. H., Lauer, J. C., &amp; Kerr, S. T. (1990). The long&#x2010;term marriage: Perceptions of stability and satisfaction. International Journal of Aging and Human Development, 31(3), 189&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenci, A. (2008). Distributional semantics in linguistic and cognitive research. Italian Journal of Linguistics, 20(1), 1&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis, M., &amp; Lupyan, G. (2020). Gender stereotypes are reflected in the distributional structure of 25 languages. Nature Human Behaviour, 4, 1021&#x2013;1028. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562&#x2010;020&#x2010;0918&#x2010;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X. L., Kuncoro, A., Hoffmann, J., d'Autume, C. D. M., Blunsom, P., &amp; Nematzadeh, A. (2021). A systematic investigation of commonsense knowledge in large language models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2111.00607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, B. Z., Nye, M., &amp; Andreas, J. (2021). Implicit representations of meaning in neural language models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2106.00737.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liesenfeld, A., &amp; Dingemanse, M. (2024). Rethinking open source generative AI: Open washing and the EU AI Act. In The 2024 ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability, and Transparency (pp. 1774&#x2013;1787).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez, B. G., &amp; Vaid, J. (2017). Psycholinguistic approaches to humor. In The Routledge handbook of language and humor (pp. 267&#x2013;281). Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahowald, K., Ivanova, A. A., Blank, I. A., Kanwisher, N., Tenenbaum, J. B., &amp; Fedorenko, E. (2024). Dissociating language and thought in large language models. Trends in Cognitive Sciences, 28(6), 517&#x2013;540</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao, J., &amp; Liu, W. (2019). A BERT&#x2010;based approach for automatic humor detection and scoring. In IberLEF@ SEPLN (pp. 197&#x2013;202).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manning, C. D. (2022). Human language understanding &amp; reasoning. Daedalus, 151(2), 127&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marjieh, R., Sucholutsky, I., van Rijn, P., Jacoby, N., &amp; Griffiths, T. (2023). What language reveals about perception: Distilling psychophysical knowledge from large language models. In Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society (Vol. 45, No. 45).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin, R. A., &amp; Ford, T. (2018). The psychology of humor: An integrative approach. Academic Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGhee, P. E., &amp; Pistolesi, E. (1979). Humor: Its origin and development. San Francisco, CA: WH Freeman.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michaelov, J. A., Bardolph, M. D., Van Petten, C. K., Bergen, B. K., &amp; Coulson, S. (2024). Strong prediction: Language model surprisal explains multiple N400 effects. Neurobiology of Language, 5(1), 107&#x2013;135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michaelov, J. A., Coulson, S., &amp; Bergen, B. K. (2022). So cloze yet so far: N400 amplitude is better predicted by distributional information than human predictability judgements. IEEE Transactions on Cognitive and Developmental Systems, 15(3), 1033&#x2013;1042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihalcea, R., &amp; Strapparava, C. (2006). Learning to laugh (automatically): Computational models for humor recognition. Computational Intelligence, 22(2), 126&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihalcea, R., Strapparava, C., &amp; Pulman, S. (2010). Computational models for incongruity detection in humour. In International Conference on Intelligent Text Processing and Computational Linguistics (pp. 364&#x2013;374). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran, J. M., Rain, M., Page&#x2010;Gould, E., &amp; Mar, R. A. (2014). Do I amuse you? Asymmetric predictors for humor appreciation and humor production. Journal of Research in Personality, 49, 8&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norrick, N. R. (1986). A frame&#x2010;theoretical analysis of verbal humor: Bisociation as schema conflict.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noveck, I. (2018). Experimental pragmatics: The making of a cognitive science. Cambridge University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raskin, V., &amp; Raskin, V. (1984). Semantic theory of humor. Semantic mechanisms of humor, (pp. 99&#x2013;147). D. Reidel.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie, G. (2001). Current directions in computational humour. Artificial Intelligence Review, 16, 119&#x2013;135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie, D. (2005). Frame&#x2010;shifting in humor and irony. Metaphor and Symbol, 20(4), 275&#x2013;294. https://doi.org/10.1207/s15327868ms2004_3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samson, A. C. (2012). The influence of empathizing and systemizing on humor processing: Theory of mind and humor. Humor, 25(1), 75&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samson, A. C., Glassco, A. L., Lee, I. A., &amp; Gross, J. J. (2014). Humorous coping and serious reappraisal: Short&#x2010;term and longer&#x2010;term effects. Europe's Journal of Psychology, 10(3), 571&#x2013;581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samson, A. C., &amp; Gross, J. J. (2012). Humour as emotion regulation: The differential consequences of negative versus positive humour. Cognition &amp; emotion, 26(2), 375&#x2013;384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samermit, P., &amp; Gibbs, Jr, R. W. (2016). Humor, the body, and cognitive linguistics. Cognitive Linguistic Studies, 3(1), 32&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer, H. (1875). The physiology of laughter. In H. Spencer (Ed.) Illustrations of universal progress: A series of discussions (pp. 194&#x2013;209). D Appleton &amp; Company. https://doi.org/10.1037/12203&#x2010;004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strick, M., Holland, R. W., Van Baaren, R. B., &amp; Van Knippenberg, A. D. (2009). Finding comfort in a joke: Consolatory effects of humor through cognitive distraction. Emotion, 9(4), 574.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suls, J. M. (1972). A two&#x2010;stage model for the appreciation of jokes and cartoons: An information&#x2010;processing analysis. In Jeffrey Goldstein &amp; Paul E. McGhee (Eds.), The psychology of humor: Theoretical perspectives and empirical issues (pp. 81&#x2013;100).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavast, M., Kunnari, A., &amp; H&#xe4;m&#xe4;l&#xe4;inen, P. (2022). Language models can generate human&#x2010;like self&#x2010;reports of emotion. In 27th International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces (pp. 69&#x2013;72).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trott, S., &amp; Bergen, B. (2021). RAW&#x2010;C: Relatedness of Ambiguous Words&#x2013;in Context (A New Lexical Resource for English). arXiv preprint arXiv:2105.13266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trott, S., Jones, C., Chang, T., Michaelov, J., &amp; Bergen, B. (2023). Do large language models know what humans know? Cognitive Science, 47(7), e13309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trott, S. (2024a). Can large language models help augment English psycholinguistic datasets? Behavior Research Methods, 56(6), 6082&#x2013;6100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trott, S. (2024b). Large language models and the wisdom of small crowds. Open Mind, 8, 723&#x2013;738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolf, T., Debut, L., Sanh, V., Chaumond, J., Delangue, C., Moi, A., Cistac, P., Rault, T., Louf, R., Funtowicz, M., Davison, J., Shleifer, S., von Platen, P., Ma, C., Jernite, Y., Plu, J., Xu, C., Scao, T. L., Gugger, S., &amp; Rush, A. M. (2020). Transformers: State&#x2010;of&#x2010;the&#x2010;art natural language processing. In Proceedings of the 2020 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing: System Demonstrations (pp. 38&#x2013;45).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, Y., Li, J., &amp; Pu, P. (2020). Uncertainty and surprisal jointly deliver the punchline: Exploiting incongruity&#x2010;based features for humor recognition. arXiv preprint arXiv:2012.12007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Z., Yuan, S., Chen, L., &amp; Yang, D. (2024). &#x201c;A good pun is its own reword&#x201d;: Can Large Language Models Understand Puns? arXiv preprint arXiv:2404.13599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yakura, H. (2024). Evaluating large language models&#x2019; ability using a psychiatric screening tool based on metaphor and sarcasm scenarios. Journal of Intelligence, 12(7), 70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziv, A. (1988). Humor's role in married life.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziv, A., &amp; Gadish, O. (1989). Humor and marital satisfaction. Journal of Social Psychology, 129(6), 759&#x2013;768.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>