<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40445459</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2730-6011</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Discover oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Discov Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessing the value of artificial intelligence-based image analysis for pre-operative surgical planning of neck dissections and iENE detection in head and neck cancer patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>956</StartPage><MedlinePgn>956</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">956</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12672-025-02798-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Accurate preoperative detection and analysis of lymph node metastasis (LNM) in head and neck squamous cell carcinoma (HNSCC) is essential for the surgical planning and execution of a neck dissection and may directly affect the morbidity and prognosis of patients. Additionally, predicting extranodal extension (ENE) using pre-operative imaging could be particularly valuable in oropharyngeal HPV-positive squamous cell carcinoma, enabling more accurate patient counseling, allowing the decision to favor primary chemoradiotherapy over immediate neck dissection when appropriate. Currently, radiological images are evaluated by radiologists and head and neck oncologists; and automated image interpretation is not part of the current standard of care. Therefore, the value of preoperative image recognition by artificial intelligence (AI) with the large language model (LLM) ChatGPT-4&#xa0;V was evaluated in this exploratory study based on neck computed tomography (CT) images of HNSCC patients with cervical LNM, and corresponding images without LNM. The objective of this study was to firstly assess the preoperative rater accuracy by comparing clinician assessments of imaging-detected extranodal extension (iENE) and the extent of neck dissection to AI predictions, and secondly to evaluate the pathology-based accuracy by comparing AI predictions to final histopathological outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">45 preoperative CT scans were retrospectively analyzed in this study: 15 cases in which a selective neck dissection (sND) was performed, 15 cases with ensuing radical neck dissection (mrND), and 15 cases without LNM (sND). Of note, image analysis was based on three single images provided to both ChatGPT-4&#xa0;V and the head and neck surgeons as reviewers. Final pathological characteristics were available in all cases as HNSCC patients had undergone surgery. ChatGPT-4&#xa0;V was tasked with providing the extent of LNM in the preoperative CT scans and with providing a recommendation for the extent of neck dissection and the detection of iENE. The diagnostic performance of ChatGPT-4&#xa0;V was reviewed independently by two head and neck surgeons with its accuracy, sensitivity, and specificity being assessed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In this study, ChatGPT-4&#xa0;V reached a sensitivity of 100% and a specificity of 34.09% in identifying the need for a radical neck dissection based on neck CT images. The sensitivity and specificity of detecting iENE was 100% and 34.15%, respectively. Both human reviewers achieved higher specificity. Notably, ChatGPT-4&#xa0;V also recommended a mrND and detected iENE on CT images without any cervical LNM.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In this exploratory study of 45 preoperative CT Neck scans before a neck dissection, ChatGPT-4&#xa0;V substantially overestimated the degree and severity of lymph node metastasis in head and neck cancer. While these results suggest that ChatGPT-4&#xa0;V may not yet be a tool providing added value for surgical planning in head and neck cancer, the unparalleled speed of analysis and well-founded reasoning provided suggests that AI tools may provide added value in the future.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schmidl</LastName><ForeName>Benedikt</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology Head and Neck Surgery, Technical University Munich, Munich, Germany. benedikt.schmidl@tum.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoch</LastName><ForeName>Cosima C</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology Head and Neck Surgery, Technical University Munich, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walter</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic and Interventional Radiology, Technical University Munich, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wirth</LastName><ForeName>Markus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology Head and Neck Surgery, RWTH Aachen University, Aachen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wollenberg</LastName><ForeName>Barbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology Head and Neck Surgery, Technical University Munich, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hussain</LastName><ForeName>Timon</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology Head and Neck Surgery, Technical University Munich, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Discov Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101775142</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2730-6011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ChatGPT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Image recognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LNM</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40445459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12672-025-02798-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s12672-025-02798-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12125457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Johnson DE, Burtness B, Leemans CR, Lui VWY, Bauman JE, Grandis JR. Head and neck squamous cell carcinoma. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2020;6(1):92&#x2013;92. 10.1038/s41572-020-00224-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7944998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33243986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon M, Roh J-L, Lee J, Cho K-J, Choi S-H, Nam SY, et al. Extranodal extension and thickness of metastatic lymph node as a significant prognostic marker of recurrence and survival in head and neck squamous cell carcinoma. J Cranio-Maxillofac Surg. 2015;43(6):769&#x2013;78. 10.1016/j.jcms.2015.04.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26027870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layland M, Sessions D, Lenox-Krug J. The influence of lymph node metastasis in the treatment of squamous cell carcinoma of the oral cavity, oropharynx, larynx, and hypopharynx: N0 versus N+. Laryngoscope. 2005;115:629&#x2013;39. 10.1097/01.mlg.0000161338.54515.b1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15805872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koroglu E, Sirin S, Isgoren S. The importance of the time interval between preoperative 18F-FDG PET/CT imaging and neck dissection for the detection of nodal metastases in patients with head and neck squamous cell carcinoma. Niger J Clin Pract. 2024;27(7):859&#x2013;64. 10.4103/njcp.njcp_38_24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39082911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horv&#xe1;th A, Prekopp P, Polony G, Sz&#xe9;kely E, Tam&#xe1;s L, D&#xe1;nos K. Accuracy of the preoperative diagnostic workup in patients with head and neck cancers undergoing neck dissection in terms of nodal metastases. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2021;278(6):2041&#x2013;6. 10.1007/s00405-020-06324-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8131330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32860560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Wit JG, Vonk J, Voskuil FJ, de Visscher S, Schepman KP, Hooghiemstra WTR, et al. EGFR-targeted fluorescence molecular imaging for intraoperative margin assessment in oral cancer patients: a phase II trial. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):4952. 10.1038/s41467-023-40324-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10432510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37587149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strohl MP, Ha PK, Flavell RR, Yom SS. PET/CT in surgical planning for head and neck cancer. Semin Nucl Med. 2021;51(1):50&#x2013;8. 10.1053/j.semnuclmed.2020.07.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33246539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Bree R, Takes RP, Shah JP, Hamoir M, Kowalski LP, Robbins KT, et al. Elective neck dissection in oral squamous cell carcinoma: past, present and future. Oral Oncol. 2019;90:87&#x2013;93. 10.1016/j.oraloncology.2019.01.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30846183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferlito A, Rinaldo A, Silver CE, Shah JP, Su&#xe1;rez C, Medina JE, et al. Neck dissection: then and now. Auris Nasus Larynx. 2006;33(4):365&#x2013;74. 10.1016/j.anl.2006.06.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16889923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deu&#xdf; E, K&#xfc;rten CHL, Meyer M, Buhr CR, K&#xfc;nzel J, Ernst B, et al. Nodal metastasis and value of neck dissection in T1/2 oropharyngeal and hypopharyngeal carcinomas. Laryngorhinootologie. 2024. 10.1055/a-2291-9979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38830380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;rten CHL, Zioga E, Gauler T, Stuschke M, Guberina M, Ludwig JM, et al. Patterns of cervical lymph node metastasis in supraglottic laryngeal cancer and therapeutic implications of surgical staging of the neck. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2021;278(12):5021&#x2013;7. 10.1007/s00405-021-06753-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8553708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33772318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benchetrit L, Torabi SJ, Givi B, Haughey B, Judson BL. Prognostic significance of extranodal extension in HPV-mediated oropharyngeal carcinoma: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2021;164(4):720&#x2013;32. 10.1177/0194599820951176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodhia VH, Penny F, Shanmugasundaram R, Patel N. De-escalating radiotherapy in HPV-positive oropharyngeal squamous cell carcinoma: how much is too little? BMJ Case Rep. 2024. 10.1136/bcr-2023-257078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10826500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38262720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nam JG, Hwang EJ, Kim J, Park N, Lee EH, Kim HJ, et al. AI improves nodule detection on chest radiographs in a health screening population: a randomized controlled trial. Radiology. 2023;307(2):e221894. 10.1148/radiol.221894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36749213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan HP, Samala RK, Hadjiiski LM. CAD and AI for breast cancer-recent development and challenges. Br J Radiol. 2020;93(1108):20190580. 10.1259/bjr.20190580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7362917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31742424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo H, Badiei Khuzani M, Vasudevan V, Huang C, Ren H, Xiao R, et al. Machine learning techniques for biomedical image segmentation: an overview of technical aspects and introduction to state-of-art applications. Med Phys. 2020;47(5):e148&#x2013;67. 10.1002/mp.13649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7338207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32418337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrmann P, Busana M, Cressoni M, Lotz J, Moerer O, Saager L, et al. Using artificial intelligence for automatic segmentation of CT lung images in acute respiratory distress syndrome. Front Physiol. 2021;12:676118. 10.3389/fphys.2021.676118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8476971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34594233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burt JR, Torosdagli N, Khosravan N, RaviPrakash H, Mortazi A, Tissavirasingham F, et al. Deep learning beyond cats and dogs: recent advances in diagnosing breast cancer with deep neural networks. Br J Radiol. 2018;91(1089):20170545. 10.1259/bjr.20170545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6223155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29565644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown M, Browning P, Wahi-Anwar MW, Murphy M, Delgado J, Greenspan H, et al. Integration of chest CT CAD into the clinical workflow and impact on radiologist efficiency. Acad Radiol. 2019;26(5):626&#x2013;31. 10.1016/j.acra.2018.07.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30097402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cascella M, Montomoli J, Bellini V, Bignami E. Evaluating the feasibility of ChatGPT in healthcare: an analysis of multiple clinical and research scenarios. J Med Syst. 2023;47(1):33. 10.1007/s10916-023-01925-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9985086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36869927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarma G, Kashyap H, Medhi PP. ChatGPT in head and neck oncology-opportunities and challenges. Ind J Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2024;76(1):1425&#x2013;9. 10.1007/s12070-023-04201-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10908741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38440617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thenappan A, Halaweish I, Mody RJ, Smith EA, Geiger JD, Ehrlich PF, et al. Review at a multidisciplinary tumor board impacts critical management decisions of pediatric patients with cancer. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2017;64(2):254&#x2013;8. 10.1002/pbc.26201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27578484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berardi R, Morgese F, Rinaldi S, Torniai M, Mentrasti G, Scortichini L, et al. Benefits and limitations of a multidisciplinary approach in cancer patient management. Cancer Manag Res. 2020;12:9363&#x2013;74. 10.2147/cmar.S220976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7533227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33061625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luchini C, Lawlor RT, Milella M, Scarpa A. Molecular tumor boards in clinical practice. Trends Cancer. 2020;6(9):738&#x2013;44. 10.1016/j.trecan.2020.05.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32517959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidl B, H&#xfc;tten T, Pigorsch S, St&#xf6;gbauer F, Hoch CC, Hussain T, et al. Assessing the role of advanced artificial intelligence as a tool in multidisciplinary tumor board decision-making for primary head and neck cancer cases. Front Oncol. 2024. 10.3389/fonc.2024.1353031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11157509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38854718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechien JR, Chiesa-Estomba CM, Baudouin R, Hans S. Accuracy of ChatGPT in head and neck oncological board decisions: preliminary findings. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2024;281(4):2105&#x2013;14. 10.1007/s00405-023-08326-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37991498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>OpenAI (2024). Image inputs for ChatGPT - FAQ.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giray L. Prompt engineering with ChatGPT: a guide for academic writers. Ann Biomed Eng. 2023;51(12):2629&#x2013;33. 10.1007/s10439-023-03272-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37284994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shifai N, van Doorn R, Malvehy J, Sangers TE. Can ChatGPT vision diagnose melanoma? An exploratory diagnostic accuracy study. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2024;90(5):1057&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.jaad.2023.12.062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38244612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehdab R, Brendlin A, Werner S, Almansour H, Gassenmaier S, Brendel JM, et al. Evaluating ChatGPT-4V in chest CT diagnostics: a critical image interpretation assessment. Jpn J Radiol. 2024. 10.1007/s11604-024-01606-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11442562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38867035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorin V, Klang E, Sklair-Levy M, Cohen I, Zippel DB, Balint Lahat N, et al. Large language model (ChatGPT) as a support tool for breast tumor board. NPJ Breast Cancer. 2023;9(1):44. 10.1038/s41523-023-00557-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10229606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37253791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massey CJ, Asokan A, Tietbohl C, Morris M, Ramakrishnan VR. Otolaryngologist perceptions of AI-based sinus CT interpretation. Am J Otolaryngol. 2023;44(5):103932. 10.1016/j.amjoto.2023.103932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37245324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham N, Ju C, Kong T, Mukherji SK. Artificial intelligence in head and neck imaging. Semin Ultrasound CT MR. 2022;43(2):170&#x2013;5. 10.1053/j.sult.2022.02.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35339257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rees CA, Litchman JH, Wu X, Servos MM, Kerr DA, Halter RJ, et al. CT for estimating adequacy of lymph node dissection in patients with squamous cell carcinoma of the head and neck. Cancer Imaging. 2021;21(1):61. 10.1186/s40644-021-00430-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8607725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34802462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teymoortash A, Hoch S, Eivazi B, Werner JA. Postoperative morbidity after different types of selective neck dissection. Laryngoscope. 2010;120(5):924&#x2013;9. 10.1002/lary.20894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20222021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Gomaa A, Semrau S, Haderlein M, Lettmaier S, Weissmann T, et al. Benchmarking ChatGPT-4 on a radiation oncology in-training exam and red journal gray zone cases: potentials and challenges for AI-assisted medical education and decision making in radiation oncology. Front Oncol. 2023;13:1265024. 10.3389/fonc.2023.1265024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10543650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37790756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes KS, Zhou J, Bao Y, Singh P, Wang J, Yin K. Natural language processing to facilitate breast cancer research and management. Breast J. 2020;26(1):92&#x2013;9. 10.1111/tbj.13718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31854067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xfc;gle T. The wide range of opportunities for large language models such as ChatGPT in rheumatology. RMD Open. 2023. 10.1136/rmdopen-2023-003105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10151992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37116985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukac S, Dayan D, Fink V, Leinert E, Hartkopf A, Veselinovic K, et al. Evaluating ChatGPT as an adjunct for the multidisciplinary tumor board decision-making in primary breast cancer cases. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2023;308(6):1831&#x2013;44. 10.1007/s00404-023-07130-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10579162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37458761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanjee Z, Crowe B, Rodman A. Accuracy of a generative artificial intelligence model in a complex diagnostic challenge. JAMA. 2023;330(1):78&#x2013;80. 10.1001/jama.2023.8288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10273128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37318797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty C, Pal S, Bhattacharya M, Dash S, Lee S-S. Overview of chatbots with special emphasis on artificial intelligence-enabled ChatGPT in medical science. Front Artif Intell. 2023. 10.3389/frai.2023.1237704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10644239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38028668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artzner C, Daubert M, Ehieli W, Kong D, Mammarappallil J, Nikolaou K, et al. Impact of computed tomography (CT)-derived fractional flow reserve on reader confidence for interpretation of coronary CT angiography. Eur J Radiol. 2018;108:242&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.ejrad.2018.09.035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30396663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mang T, Hermosillo G, Wolf M, Bogoni L, Salganicoff M, Raykar V, et al. Time-efficient CT colonography interpretation using an advanced image-gallery-based, computer-aided &#x201c;first-reader&#x201d; workflow for the detection of colorectal adenomas. Eur Radiol. 2012;22(12):2768&#x2013;79. 10.1007/s00330-012-2522-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22903619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu HH, Ko KH, Chou YC, Wu YC, Chiu SH, Chang CK, et al. Performance and reading time of lung nodule identification on multidetector CT with or without an artificial intelligence-powered computer-aided detection system. Clin Radiol. 2021;76(8):626.e623-626.e632. 10.1016/j.crad.2021.04.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34023068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal M, Goswami A, Sharma P. Evaluating ChatGPT-3.5 and claude-2 in answering and explaining conceptual medical physiology multiple-choice questions. Cureus. 2023;15(9):e46222. 10.7759/cureus.46222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10613833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37908959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldonazzi N, Rizzo PC, Eccher A, Girolami I, Fanelli GN, Naccarato AG, et al. Value of artificial intelligence in evaluating lymph node metastases. Cancers. 2023. 10.3390/cancers15092491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10177013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37173958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen CR, Christiansen RL, Lorenzen EL, Bertelsen AS, Asmussen JT, Gyldenkerne N, et al. Contouring and dose calculation in head and neck cancer radiotherapy after reduction of metal artifacts in CT images. Acta Oncol. 2017;56(6):874&#x2013;8. 10.1080/0284186x.2017.1287427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28464749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunqueiro A, Gomes WA, Lee P, Dym RJ, Scheinfeld MH. CT of the neck: image analysis and reporting in the emergency setting. Radiographics. 2019;39(6):1760&#x2013;81. 10.1148/rg.2019190012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31589582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Wu L, Wang Y, Sheng B, Tham YC, Ji H, et al. Unexpectedly low accuracy of GPT-4 in identifying common liver diseases from CT scan images. Dig Liver Dis. 2024;56(4):718&#x2013;20. 10.1016/j.dld.2024.01.191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38311531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keshavarz P, Bagherieh S, Nabipoorashrafi SA, Chalian H, Rahsepar AA, Kim GHJ, et al. ChatGPT in radiology: a systematic review of performance, pitfalls, and future perspectives. Diagn Interv Imaging. 2024;105(7):251&#x2013;65. 10.1016/j.diii.2024.04.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38679540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Liu H, Han J, Xu S, Zhang G, Wang Q, et al. Ultra-low-dose CT lung screening with artificial intelligence iterative reconstruction: evaluation via automatic nodule-detection software. Clin Radiol. 2023;78(7):525&#x2013;31. 10.1016/j.crad.2023.01.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36948944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mastouri R, Khlifa N, Neji H, Hantous-Zannad S. Deep learning-based CAD schemes for the detection and classification of lung nodules from CT images: a survey. J Xray Sci Technol. 2020;28(4):591&#x2013;617. 10.3233/xst-200660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32568165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawahara D, Tsuneda M, Ozawa S, Okamoto H, Nakamura M, Nishio T, et al. Deep learning-based auto segmentation using generative adversarial network on magnetic resonance images obtained for head and neck cancer patients. J Appl Clin Med Phys. 2022;23(5):e13579. 10.1002/acm2.13579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9121028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35263027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikolov S, Blackwell S, Zverovitch A, Mendes R, Livne M, De Fauw J, et al. Clinically applicable segmentation of head and neck anatomy for radiotherapy: deep learning algorithm development and validation study. J Med Internet Res. 2021;23(7):e26151. 10.2196/26151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8314151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34255661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paudyal R, Shah AD, Akin O, Do RKG, Konar AS, Hatzoglou V, et al. Artificial intelligence in CT and MR imaging for oncological applications. Cancers. 2023. 10.3390/cancers15092573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10177423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37174039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>OuYang PY, He Y, Guo JG, Liu JN, Wang ZL, Li A, et al. Artificial intelligence aided precise detection of local recurrence on MRI for nasopharyngeal carcinoma: a multicenter cohort study. EClinicalMedicine. 2023;63:102202. 10.1016/j.eclinm.2023.102202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10480520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37680944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei X, Jiang J, Cao W, Yu H, Deng H, Chen J, et al. Artificial intelligence assistance improves the accuracy and efficiency of intracranial aneurysm detection with CT angiography. Eur J Radiol. 2022;149:110169. 10.1016/j.ejrad.2022.110169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35139447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kundu R, Singh PK, Mirjalili S, Sarkar R. COVID-19 detection from lung CT-scans using a fuzzy integral-based CNN ensemble. Comput Biol Med. 2021;138:104895. 10.1016/j.compbiomed.2021.104895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8483997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34649147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho P, Baldwin D, Carter R, Parsons C. Accuracy of CT in detecting squamous carcinoma metastases in cervical lymph nodes. Clin Radiol. 1991;44(2):79&#x2013;81. 10.1016/s0009-9260(05)80500-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1884590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wendt M, Hammarstedt-Nordenvall L, Zupancic M, Friesland S, Landin D, Munck-Wikland E, et al. Long-term survival and recurrence in oropharyngeal squamous cell carcinoma in relation to subsites, HPV, and p16-status. Cancers. 2021. 10.3390/cancers13112553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8196945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34070952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henson C, Abou-Foul AK, Yu E, Glastonbury C, Huang SH, King AD, et al. Criteria for the diagnosis of extranodal extension detected on radiological imaging in head and neck cancer: head and neck cancer international group consensus recommendations. Lancet Oncol. 2024;25(7):e297&#x2013;307. 10.1016/S1470-2045(24)00066-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38936388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullock MJ, Beitler JJ, Carlson DL, Fonseca I, Hunt JL, Katabi N, et al. Data set for the reporting of nodal excisions and neck dissection specimens for head and neck tumors: explanations and recommendations of the guidelines from the international collaboration on cancer reporting. Arch Pathol Lab Med. 2019;143(4):452&#x2013;62. 10.5858/arpa.2018-0421-SA.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30500291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schonfeld E, Pant A, Shah A, Sadeghzadeh S, Pangal D, Rodrigues A, et al. Evaluating computer vision, large language, and genome-wide association models in a limited sized patient cohort for pre-operative risk stratification in adult spinal deformity surgery. J Clin Med. 2024. 10.3390/jcm13030656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10856542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38337352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu H, Ehwerhemuepha L, Rakovski C. A comparative study on deep learning models for text classification of unstructured medical notes with various levels of class imbalance. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2022;22(1):181. 10.1186/s12874-022-01665-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9250736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35780100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sehar U, Kanwal S, Allheeib NI, Almari S, Khan F, Dashtipur K, et al. A hybrid dependency-based approach for Urdu sentiment analysis. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):22075. 10.1038/s41598-023-48817-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10716113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38086933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Mohamad F, Donle L, Dorfner F, Romanescu L, Drechsler K, Wattjes MP, et al. Open-source large language models can generate labels from radiology reports for training convolutional neural networks. Acad Radiol. 2025. 10.1016/j.acra.2024.12.028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39765434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teramoto A, Michiba A, Kiriyama Y, Tsukamoto T, Imaizumi K, Fujita H. Automated description generation of cytologic findings for lung cytological images using a pretrained vision model and dual text decoders: preliminary study. Cytopathology. 2025. 10.1111/cyt.13474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39918342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh Y, Park S, Byun HK, Cho Y, Lee IJ, Kim JS, et al. LLM-driven multimodal target volume contouring in radiation oncology. Nat Commun. 2024;15(1):9186. 10.1038/s41467-024-53387-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11502670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39448587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benary M, Wang XD, Schmidt M, Soll D, Hilfenhaus G, Nassir M, et al. Leveraging large language models for decision support in personalized oncology. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6(11):e2343689. 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.43689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10656647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37976064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Shi E, Yu S, Wu Z, Ma C, Dai H, et al. Prompt engineering for healthcare: methodologies and applications. arXiv preprint. 2023. 10.4855/arXiv.2304.14670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang C-H, Weng C-L, Chiu H-W. Automatic classification of medical image modality and anatomical location using convolutional neural network. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(6):e0253205. 10.1371/journal.pone.0253205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8195382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34115822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mai HN, Lee DH. Effects of exposure parameters and voxel size for cone-beam computed tomography on the image matching accuracy with an optical dental scan image: an in vitro study. Biomed Res Int. 2021;2021:6971828. 10.1155/2021/6971828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8213486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34222482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh DM, Papanikolaou N, Bick U, Illing R, Kahn CE Jr, Kalpathi-Cramer J, et al. Artificial intelligence and machine learning in cancer imaging. Commun Med. 2022;2:133. 10.1038/s43856-022-00199-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9613681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36310650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caon M. Voxel-based computational models of real human anatomy: a review. Radiat Environ Biophys. 2004;42(4):229&#x2013;35. 10.1007/s00411-003-0221-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14730450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Sch&#xf6;neck M, Beyan O, Caldeira LL. Voxel-wise medical imaging transformation and adaption based on CycleGAN and score-based diffusion. Stud Health Technol Inform. 2023;302:1027&#x2013;8. 10.3233/shti230337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37203572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palma G, Monti S, Cella L. Voxel-based analysis in radiation oncology: a methodological cookbook. Phys Med. 2020;69:192&#x2013;204. 10.1016/j.ejmp.2019.12.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31923757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng L, Wang T, Zhai Z, Tao W, Li J, et al. Evaluation of large language models in breast cancer clinical scenarios: a comparative analysis based on ChatGPT-3.5, ChatGPT-4.0, and Claude2. Int J Surg. 2024;110(4):1941&#x2013;50. 10.1097/js9.0000000000001066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11019981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38668655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechien JR, Maniaci A, Gengler I, Hans S, Chiesa-Estomba CM, Vaira LA. Validity and reliability of an instrument evaluating the performance of intelligent chatbot: the artificial intelligence performance instrument (AIPI). Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2024;281(4):2063&#x2013;79. 10.1007/s00405-023-08219-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37698703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechien JR, Georgescu BM, Hans S, Chiesa-Estomba CM. ChatGPT performance in laryngology and head and neck surgery: a clinical case-series. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2023. 10.1007/s00405-023-08282-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37874336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallistl V, Banday MUL, Berridge C, Grigorovich A, Jarke J, Mannheim I, et al. Addressing the black box of AI&#x2014;a model and research agenda on the co-constitution of aging and artificial intelligence. Gerontologist. 2024. 10.1093/geront/gnae039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11134299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38700416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uprety D, Zhu D, West HJ. ChatGPT-A promising generative AI tool and its implications for cancer care. Cancer. 2023;129(15):2284&#x2013;9. 10.1002/cncr.34827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37183438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>