<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40450381</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2473-4209</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical physics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Phys</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physical phantom validation of clustering-initiated factorization in dynamic PET.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mp.17902</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Dynamic positron emission tomography (PET) enables the quantification of physiological parameters of radiotracers employed in the investigation of neuropsychiatric disorders. We previously introduced a factor analysis-based algorithm, Cluster-Initialized Factor Analysis (CIFA), designed to overcome the problem of specifying reference regions. CIFA is capable of automatically extracting distinct radiotracer binding distributions across many modalities based on the differences in tracer dynamics, and thus can distinguish regions of specific- and non-specific binding without requiring prior segmentation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Our goal is to quantitatively validate the ability of CIFA to resolve different dynamic biological processes by comparing the output of the algorithm to an independent benchmark. As an intermediate goal, we aim to create a physical phantom capable of modeling unique aspects of dynamic imaging and to use this phantom as the benchmark in evaluating&#xa0;CIFA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">CIFA was used to reconstruct <sup>18</sup>F-flortaucipir dynamic brain PET datasets acquired at Lawrence Berkeley National Lab. The resulting factor curves served as the foundation for creating dynamic input time-activity curve (TAC) combinations in a physical brain phantom specifically constructed for this purpose. The phantom represented three components: two overlapping tissue types and free radiotracer, constructed with a combination of small hydraulic elements. The physical components were scanned separately to generate a library of images, allowing us to reproduce scans of any duration with prescribed dynamics and realistic partial volume effects. The phantom was designed to produce noisy instances with compartment mixing of dynamic scans with desired activity TACs for free, non-specifically bound, and specifically bound radiotracers. Ten distinct dynamic simulations with varying levels of TAC similarity were estimated with&#xa0;CIFA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We directly evaluated CIFA's performance in analyzing each of the 10 dynamic datasets by computing the Pearson correlation coefficient between the estimated outputs and the ground truth tissue TACs and corresponding tissue distributions. For seven out of 10 modeled dynamics, which captured the full spectrum of realistically expected tissue TAC shapes, the curve correlation of the specific binding tissue was above 95%.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This work formulated an innovative process by combining a physical phantom design with PET images for evaluating the application of CIFA in the extraction of dynamic TACs from dynamic PET image data. In most cases the CIFA algorithm accurately reproduced the dynamics of the phantom simulated&#xa0;data.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 American Association of Physicists in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kobzarenko</LastName><ForeName>Valerie</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>BioComputing Lab, Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, Florida Institute of Technology, Melbourne, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baker</LastName><ForeName>Suzanne L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Molecular Biophysics and Integrated Bioimaging, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, Berkeley, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Janabi</LastName><ForeName>Mustafa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Molecular Biophysics and Integrated Bioimaging, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, Berkeley, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choong</LastName><ForeName>Woon-Seng</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Molecular Biophysics and Integrated Bioimaging, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, Berkeley, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gullberg</LastName><ForeName>Grant T</ForeName><Initials>GT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Biomedical Imaging, University of California, San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seo</LastName><ForeName>Youngho</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Biomedical Imaging, University of California, San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boutchko</LastName><ForeName>Rostyslav</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>SolvingDynamics, Inc.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mitra</LastName><ForeName>Debasis</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>BioComputing Lab, Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, Florida Institute of Technology, Melbourne, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R15EB030807</GrantID><Acronym>NH</Acronym><Agency>NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01HL135490</GrantID><Acronym>NH</Acronym><Agency>NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R43AG059500-01</GrantID><Acronym>NH</Acronym><Agency>NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>1819453</GrantID><Agency>National Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Phys</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0425746</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0094-2405</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FADS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PET</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical phantom</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40450381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mp.17902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Lammertsma AA. Forward to the past: the case for quantitative PET imaging. J Nucl Med. 2017;7:1019&#x2010;1024. doi: 10.2967/jnumed.116.188029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ametamey SM, Honer M, Schubiger PA. Molecular imaging with PET. Chem Rev. 2008;5:1501&#x2010;1516. doi: 10.1021/cr0782426</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimitrakopoulou&#x2010;Strauss A, Pan L, Sachpekidis C. Kinetic modeling and parametric imaging with dynamic PET for oncological applications: general considerations, current clinical applications, and future perspectives. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2020;1:21&#x2010;39. doi: 10.1007/s00259&#x2010;020&#x2010;04843&#x2010;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Innis RB, Cunningham VJ, Delforge J, et&#xa0;al. Consensus nomenclature for in vivo imaging of reversibly binding radioligands. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2007;9:1533&#x2010;1539. doi: 10.1038/sj.jcbfm.9600493</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frid&#xe9;n M, Wennerberg M, Antonsson M, Sandberg&#x2010;St&#xe4;ll M, Farde L, Schou M. Identification of positron emission tomography (PET) tracer candidates by prediction of the target&#x2010;bound fraction in the brain. EJNMMI Res. 2014;4(1):50. doi: 10.1186/s13550&#x2010;014&#x2010;0050&#x2010;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E, Varrone A, Boellaard R, et&#xa0;al. EANM procedure guidelines for brain PET imaging using [18F]FDG, version 3. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;2:632&#x2013;651. doi: 10.1007/s00259&#x2010;021&#x2010;05603&#x2010;w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaquero JJ, Kinahan P. Positron emission tomography: current challenges and opportunities for technological advances in clinical and preclinical imaging systems. Annu Rev Biomed Eng. 2015;1:385&#x2010;414. doi: 10.1146/annurev&#x2010;bioeng&#x2010;071114&#x2010;040723</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunn RN, Gunn SR, Cunningham VJ. Positron emission tomography compartmental models. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2001;6:635&#x2010;652. doi: 10.1097/00004647&#x2010;200106000&#x2010;00002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunn RN, Gunn SR, Turkheimer FE, Aston JAD, Cunningham VJ. Positron emission tomography compartmental models: a basis pursuit strategy for kinetic modeling. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2002;22(12):1425&#x2010;1439. doi: 10.1097/00004647&#x2010;200212000&#x2010;00003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanotti&#x2010;Fregonara P, Chen K, Liow JS, Fujita M, Innis RB. Image&#x2010;derived input function for brain PET studies: many challenges and few opportunities. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2011;10:1986&#x2010;1998. doi: 10.1038/jcbfm.2011.107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salinas CA, Searle GE, Gunn RN. The simplified reference tissue model: model assumption violations and their impact on binding potential. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2014;2:304&#x2010;311. doi: 10.1038/jcbfm.2014.202</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Ng YL, Paranjpe MD, et&#xa0;al. Tracer&#x2010;specific reference tissues selection improves detection of 18F&#x2010;FDG, 18F&#x2010;florbetapir, and 18F&#x2010;flortaucipir PET SUVR changes in Alzheimer's disease. Hum Brain Mapp. 2022;7:2121&#x2010;2133. doi: 10.1002/hbm.25774</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boellaard R, Krak NC, Hoekstra OS, Lammertsma AA. Effects of noise, image resolution, and ROI definition on the accuracy of standard uptake values: a simulation study. J Nucl Med. 2004;9:1519&#x2013;1527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinahan PE, Fletcher JW. Positron emission tomography&#x2010;computed tomography standardized uptake values in clinical practice and assessing response to therapy. Semin Ultrasound CT MR. 2010;6:496&#x2010;505. doi: 10.1053/j.sult.2010.10.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logan J. A review of graphical methods for tracer studies and strategies to reduce bias. Nucl Med Biol. 2003;8:833&#x2010;844. doi: 10.1016/s0969&#x2010;8051(03)00114&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patlak CS, Blasberg RG, Fenstermacher JD. Graphical evaluation of blood&#x2010;to&#x2010;brain transfer constants from multiple&#x2010;time uptake data. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 1983;1:1&#x2010;7. doi: 10.1038/jcbfm.1983.1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertoldo A, Rizzo G, Veronese M. Deriving physiological information from PET images: from SUV to compartmental modelling. Clin Transl Imaging. 2014;3:239&#x2010;251. doi: 10.1007/s40336&#x2010;014&#x2010;0067&#x2010;x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettinardi V, Castiglioni I, Bernardi ED, Gilardi MC. PET quantification: strategies for partial volume correction. Clin Transl Imaging. 2014;3:199&#x2010;218. doi: 10.1007/s40336&#x2010;014&#x2010;0066&#x2010;y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soret M, Bacharach SL, Buvat I. Partial&#x2010;volume effect in PET tumor imaging. J Nucl Med. 2007;6:932&#x2010;945. doi: 10.2967/jnumed.106.035774</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turkheimer FE, Paul Edison NP, Roncaroli F, et&#xa0;al. Reference and target region modeling of [11C${11}\mathrm{C}$]&#x2010;(R)&#x2010;PK11195 brain studies. J Nucl Med. 2007;1:158&#x2010;167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabinovici GD, Jagust WJ, Furst AJ, et&#xa0;al. A&#x3b2;${\rm A}\beta$ amyloid and glucose metabolism in three variants of primary progressive aphasia. Ann Neurol. 2008;4:388&#x2010;401. doi: 10.1002/ana.21451</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ossenkoppele R, Schonhaut DR, Sch&#xf6;ll M, et&#xa0;al. Tau PET patterns mirror clinical and neuroanatomical variability in Alzheimer's disease. Brain. 2016;5:1551&#x2010;1567. doi: 10.1093/brain/aww027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sitek A, Bella ED, Gullberg G. Factor analysis of dynamic structures in dynamic SPECT imaging using maximum entropy. IEEE Trans Nucl Sci. 1999;6:2227&#x2010;2232. doi: 10.1109/23.819308</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutchko R, Mitra D, Baker SL, Jagust WJ, Gullberg GT. Clustering&#x2010;initiated factor analysis application for tissue classification in dynamic brain positron emission tomography. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2015;7:1104&#x2010;1111. doi: 10.1038/jcbfm.2015.69</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segars WP, Tsui BMW. MCAT to XCAT: the evolution of 4&#x2010;D computerized phantoms for imaging research. Proc IEEE. 2009;12:1954&#x2010;1968. doi: 10.1109/jproc.2009.2022417</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krakovich A, Zaretsky U, Moalem I, et&#xa0;al. A new cardiac phantom for dynamic SPECT. J Nucl Cardiol. 2021;5:2299&#x2010;2309. doi: 10.1007/s12350&#x2010;020&#x2010;02028&#x2010;0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahey F, Christian P, Zukotynski K, et&#xa0;al. Use of a qualification phantom for PET brain imaging in a multicenter consortium: a collaboration between the pediatric brain tumor consortium and the SNMMI clinical trials network. J Nucl Med. 2018;5:677&#x2010;682. doi: 10.2967/jnumed.118.219998</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macleod M, Houston A. Factor analysis of dynamic structures (FADS) in the diagnosis of renal disease. European J Nucl Med. 1989;15:601&#x2010;604. doi: 10.1007/bf00256937</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker SL, Lockhart SN, Price JC, et&#xa0;al. Reference tissue&#x2013;based kinetic evaluation of 18F&#x2010;AV&#x2010;1451 for tau imaging. J Nucl Med. 2016;2:332&#x2010;338. doi: 10.2967/jnumed.116.175273</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price JC, Klunk WE, Lopresti BJ, et&#xa0;al. Kinetic modeling of amyloid binding in humans using PET imaging and Pittsburgh Compound&#x2010;B. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2005;11:1528&#x2010;1547. doi: 10.1038/sj.jcbfm.9600146</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sitek A, Reutter BW, Huesman RH, Gullberg GT. Method of generating multiple sets of experimental phantom data. J Nucl Med. 2006;7:1187&#x2010;1192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khamar R, Kobzarenko V, Mitra D. Early breast cancer detection with ultrasound using NMF. Medical Imaging 2025: Ultrasonic Imaging and Tomography. In: Mehrmohammadi M, Boehm C, eds. 2025:3. doi: 10.1117/12.3046130</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdalah M, Boutchko R, Mitra D, Gullberg GT. Reconstruction of 4&#x2010;D dynamic SPECT images from inconsistent projections using a spline initialized FADS algorithm (SIFADS). IEEE Trans Med Imaging. 2015;1:216&#x2010;228. doi: 10.1109/tmi.2014.2352033</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huh Y, Shrestha UM, Gullberg GT, Seo Y. Monte Carlo simulation and reconstruction: assessment of myocardial perfusion imaging of tracer dynamics with cardiac motion due to deformation and respiration using gamma camera with continuous acquisition. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2022;9. doi: 10.3389/fcvm.2022.871967</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobzarenko V, Shrestha UM, Gullberg GT, Seo Y, Mitra D. Dynamic spatiotemporal clustering for factor analysis in dynamic structures. In: Proceedings of the 17th International Meeting on Fully 3D Image Reconstruction in Radiology and Nuclear Medicine. 2023:203&#x2010;206. doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2310.16846</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>