<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40450337</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1477-7525</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Health and quality of life outcomes</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Health Qual Life Outcomes</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The association of post-COVID-19 fatigue in the acute phase with neuropsychiatric and neurocognitive symptoms trajectory over time and long-term health-related quality of life among Chinese adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>54</StartPage><MedlinePgn>54</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12955-025-02384-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Post-viral fatigue is a common and debilitating neurological sequela of COVID-19, often accompanied with multidimensional neuropsychiatric symptoms (post-viral fatigue, sleep disturbance, anxiety, depression, and post-traumatic stress disorder) and neurocognitive impairment. We sought to characterize the trajectory of these neurological symptoms and investigate the relationship between acute-phase fatigue (&lt;&#x2009;1&#xa0;month) and the chronicity of neuropsychiatric and neurocognitive symptoms, as well as long-term health-related quality of life (HRQoL) at 3&#xa0;months post-infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A prospective, multi-center, longitudinal study was conducted from January to February 2023 within a cohort of individuals with a mild SARS-COV-2 infection and contemporaneous healthy controls (HCs). Comprehensive neuropsychiatric and neurocognitive assessments were collected for COVID-19 survivors during both acute and chronic phase post-infection, with the EQ-5D-5L (a standardized instrument for assessing HRQoL) evaluated at the chronic phase. Healthy controls underwent the same protocol for recruitment to the study. Linear mixed models were used to access the impact of acute-phase fatigue on different neuropsychiatric and neurocognitive scales over time.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Three hundred thirty-five COVID-19 survivors and 79 HCs were included in the study. COVID-19 survivors exhibited poorer performance in various neuropsychiatric domains during the acute phase, with the exception of cognitive impairment. A significant amelioration of emotional symptoms, including anxiety and depression, was observed from the acute to chronic phase among COVID-19 survivors, reaching levels comparable to those of HCs. However, at 3&#xa0;months post-infection, survivors continued to report higher levels of fatigue and poorer sleep quality compared to HCs, although the differences had diminished from the acute phase. The impact of the pandemic event persisted, and no significant changes in cognitive performance were observed. Acute-phase fatigue was associated with poorer sleep and worse emotional problems during the recovery process (from the acute to the chronic phase), and further exacerbated overall HRQoL at 3&#xa0;months post-infection (EQ index score, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001, Cohen's d&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.33; EQ-VAS, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.007, Cohen's d&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.19).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings provide novel evidence on the distinct temporal trajectories for post-acute COVID-19 sequelae in a longitudinal study, highlighting the negative impact of acute-phase fatigue on the process of neuropsychiatric recovery and long-term HRQoL.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Qiange</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging, the First Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University, 277 West Yanta Road, Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, 710061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quan</LastName><ForeName>Xingpu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging, the First Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University, 277 West Yanta Road, Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, 710061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Zhaoyao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging, the First Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University, 277 West Yanta Road, Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, 710061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shang</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Future Technology, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Xinyi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging, the First Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University, 277 West Yanta Road, Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, 710061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bao</LastName><ForeName>Wenrui</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Future Technology, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shang</LastName><ForeName>Meiling</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Future Technology, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Peng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, the Second Hospital of the Air Force Medical University, Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging, Nuclear 215 Hospital of Shaanxi Province, Xianyang, Shaanxi Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Fan</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Research Centre, the First Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Wenyang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging, the First Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University, 277 West Yanta Road, Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, 710061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Ziyi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Science Center, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niu</LastName><ForeName>Xuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1580-0209</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging, the First Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University, 277 West Yanta Road, Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, 710061, China. niuxuan@xjtu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yuchen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, the First Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, China. zhangyc415@xjtu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>xzy022023078</GrantID><Agency>Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities in Xi'an Jiaotong University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>xzy012023128</GrantID><Agency>Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities in Xi'an Jiaotong University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>L2023-ZDYF-SF-035</GrantID><Agency>Key Research and Development Plan of Xianyang City</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>61240302</GrantID><Agency>the Science and Technology Research Project of Shaanxi Nuclear Industry Group Co., Ltd</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>82202121</GrantID><Agency>the National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023PT-09</GrantID><Agency>Health Research and Innovation Capacity Strengthening Platform Program of Shaanxi Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Health Qual Life Outcomes</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101153626</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1477-7525</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Linear mixed models</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurocognitive impairment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropsychiatric symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-viral fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Trajectory</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Ethics approval was obtained from the Ethics Committee of the First Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University, which approved this study (No. XJTU1AF2023LSK-013). Informed consent was obtained from all individual participants included in the study. Consent for publication: The manuscript does not contain any individual person's data in any form (including individual details, images, or videos). Therefore, consent for publication is not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40450337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12955-025-02384-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12955-025-02384-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amerio A, Aguglia A, Odone A, Gianfredi V, Serafini G, Signorelli C, et al. Covid-19 pandemic impact on mental health of vulnerable populations. Acta Biomed. 2020;91(9-S):95&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.23750/abm.v91i9-S.10112 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambrosetti JA-O, Macheret L, Folliet A, Wullschleger A, Amerio AA-OX, Aguglia A, et al. Psychiatric emergency admissions during and after COVID-19 lockdown: short-term impact and long-term implications on mental health. BMC Psychiatry. 2021;21(1):465. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12888-021-03469-8 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye G, Zhu Y, Bao W, Zhou H, Lai J, Zhang Y, et al. The Long COVID Symptoms and Severity Score: Development, Validation, and Application. Value Health. 2024;27(8):1085&#x2013;91. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jval.2024.04.009 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jval.2024.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38641060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahorsu DK, Lin CY, Imani V, Saffari M, Griffiths MD, Pakpour AH. The Fear of COVID-19 Scale: Development and Initial Validation. Int J Ment Health Addict. 2022;20(3):1537&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11469-020-00270-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11469-020-00270-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32226353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor S, Landry CA, Paluszek MM, Fergus TA, McKay D, Asmundson GJG. Development and initial validation of the COVID Stress Scales. J Anxiety Disord. 2020;72: 102232. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.janxdis.2020.102232 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.janxdis.2020.102232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32408047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7198206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badenoch JB, Rengasamy ER, Watson C, Jansen K, Chakraborty S, Sundaram RD, et al. Persistent neuropsychiatric symptoms after COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Commun. 2022;4(1):fcab297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanbehzadeh S, Tavahomi M, Zanjari N, Ebrahimi-Takamjani I, Amiri-Arimi S. Physical and mental health complications post-COVID-19: Scoping review. J Psychosom Res. 2021;147: 110525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34051516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8133797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychores.2021.110525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batawi S, Tarazan N, Al-Raddadi R, Qasim EA, Alraddadi BM. Quality of life reported by survivors after hospitalization for Middle East respiratory syndrome (MERS). Health and Quality of Life Outcomes. 2019;17(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Ling S, Lui LMW, Lee Y, Gill H, Teopiz KM, et al. Fatigue and cognitive impairment in Post-COVID-19 Syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun. 2022;101:93&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34973396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2021.12.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moldofsky H, Patcai J. Chronic widespread musculoskeletal pain, fatigue, depression and disordered sleep in chronic post-SARS syndrome; a case-controlled study. Bmc Neurology. 2011;11(1):37-.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matschke J, L&#xfc;tgehetmann M, Hagel C, Sperhake JP, Schr&#xf6;der AS, Edler C, et al. Neuropathology of patients with COVID-19 in Germany: a post-mortem case series. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19(11):919&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7535629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30308-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song E, Zhang C, Israelow B, Lu-Culligan A, Prado AV, Skriabine S, et al. Neuroinvasion of SARS-CoV-2 in human and mouse brain. J Exp Med. 2021;218(3).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein SR, Ramelli SC, Grazioli A, Chung JY, Singh M, Yinda CK, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection and persistence in the human body and brain at autopsy. Nature. 2022;612(7941):758&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36517603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9749650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-022-05542-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortelli P, Ferrazzoli D, Sebastianelli L, Engl M, Versace V. Neuropsychological and neurophysiological correlates of fatigue in post-acute patients with neurological manifestations of COVID-19: Insights into a challenging symptom. J Neurol Sci. 2021;420(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versace V, Sebastianelli L, Ferrazzoli D, Romanello R, Ortelli P, Saltuari L, et al. Intracortical GABAergic dysfunction in patients with fatigue and dysexecutive syndrome after COVID-19. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132(5):1138&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33774378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7954785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinph.2021.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E, Campion JY, Dudouet P, Kaphan E, Bregeon F, Tissot-Dupont H, et al. (18)F-FDG brain PET hypometabolism in patients with long COVID. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48(9):2823&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33501506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7837643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-021-05215-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morand A, Campion JY, Lepine A, Bosdure E, Luciani L, Cammilleri S, et al. Similar patterns of [(18)F]-FDG brain PET hypometabolism in paediatric and adult patients with long COVID: a paediatric case series. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2022;49(3):913&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34414470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-021-05528-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sollini M, Morbelli S, Ciccarelli M, Cecconi M, Aghemo A, Morelli P, et al. Long COVID hallmarks on [18F]FDG-PET/CT: a case-control study. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48(10):3187&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33677642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7937050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-021-05294-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos MC, Nery T, Starke AC, de Bem Alves AC, Speck AE, A SA. Post-viral fatigue in COVID-19: A review of symptom assessment methods, mental, cognitive, and physical impairment. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2022;142:104902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Bermingham C, Pouwels KB, Glickman M, Nafilyan V, Zaccardi F, et al. Trajectory of long covid symptoms after covid-19 vaccination: community based cohort study. BMJ. 2022;377: e069676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35584816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2021-069676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haffke M, Freitag H, Rudolf G, Seifert M, Doehner W, Scherbakov N, et al. Endothelial dysfunction and altered endothelial biomarkers in patients with post-COVID-19 syndrome and chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). J Transl Med. 2022;20(1):138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35317812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8938726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-022-03346-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza MG, Palladini M, Villa G, De Lorenzo R, Rovere Querini P, Benedetti F. Prevalence, trajectory over time, and risk factor of post-COVID-19 fatigue. J Psychiatr Res. 2022;155:112&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36029623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9391361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2022.08.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son K, Jamil R, Chowdhury A, Mukherjee M, Venegas C, Miyasaki K, et al. Circulating anti-nuclear autoantibodies in COVID-19 survivors predict long COVID symptoms. Eur Respir J. 2023;61(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabria M, Garc&#xed;a-S&#xe1;nchez C, Grunden N, Pons C, Arroyo JA, G&#xf3;mez-Anson B, et al. Post-COVID-19 fatigue: the contribution of cognitive and neuropsychiatric symptoms. J Neurol. 2022;269(8):3990&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35488918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9055007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-022-11141-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudroff T, Fietsam AC, Deters JR, Bryant AD, Kamholz J. Post-COVID-19 Fatigue: Potential Contributing Factors. Brain Sci. 2020;10(12).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudroff T, Workman CD, Bryant AD. Potential Factors That Contribute to Post-COVID-19 Fatigue in Women. Brain Sci. 2022;12(5).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Houwelingen F, van Dellen E, Visser-Meily JMA, Valkenet K, Heijnen GH, Vernooij LM, et al. Mental, cognitive and physical outcomes after intensive care unit treatment during the COVID-19 pandemic: a comparison between COVID-19 and non-COVID-19 patients. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):14414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37660228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10475104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-41667-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Naamani Z, Gormley K, Noble H, Santin O, Al MM. Fatigue, anxiety, depression and sleep quality in patients undergoing haemodialysis. BMC Nephrol. 2021;22(1):157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33910523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8080199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12882-021-02349-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou S, Liu ZH, Yan X, Wang H, Li Y, Xu X, et al. Prevalence and correlates of fatigue and its association with quality of life among clinically stable older psychiatric patients during the COVID-19 outbreak: a cross-sectional study. Global Health. 2020;16(1):119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33339523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7748982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12992-020-00644-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labrague LJ. Pandemic fatigue and clinical nurses&#x2019; mental health, sleep quality and job contentment during the covid-19 pandemic: The mediating role of resilience. J Nurs Manag. 2021;29(7):1992&#x2013;2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34018270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jonm.13383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YJ, Shih TS, Wu WT, Guo YL. The association of job fatigue with mental disorders among bus drivers. Scand J Work Environ Health. 2023;49(1):75&#x2013;83. https://doi.org/10.5271/sjweh.4065 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5271/sjweh.4065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36265132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michielsen HJ, Vries JD, Heck GLV, Vijver FJRVD, Sijtsma K. Examination of the Dimensionality of Fatigue. European Journal of Psychological Assessment. 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jolanda, de, Vries, Helen, Michielsen, Guus, et al. Measuring fatigue in sarcoidosis: The Fatigue Assessment Scale (FAS). British Journal of Health Psychology. 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xe5;ndal A, Eriksson M, Wester P, Lundin-Olsson L. Reliability and validity of the Swedish Fatigue Assessment Scale when self-administrered by persons with mild to moderate stroke. Top Stroke Rehabil. 2016;23(2):90&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26883993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10749357.2015.1112057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendriks C, Drent M, Elfferich M, De Vries J. The Fatigue Assessment Scale: quality and availability in sarcoidosis and other diseases. Curr Opin Pulm Med. 2018;24(5):495&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29889115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCP.0000000000000496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nopp S, Moik F, Klok FA, Gattinger D, Petrovic M, Vonbank K, et al. Outpatient Pulmonary Rehabilitation in Patients with Long COVID Improves Exercise Capacity, Functional Status, Dyspnea, Fatigue, and Quality of Life. Respiration. 2022;101(6):593&#x2013;601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35203084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000522118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck AT, Epstein N, Brown G, Steer RA. An inventory for measuring clinical anxiety: psychometric properties. J Consult Clin Psychol. 1988;56(6):893&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3204199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-006X.56.6.893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steer RA, Clark DA, Beck AT, Ranieri WF. Common and specific dimensions of self-reported anxiety and depression: the BDI-II versus the BDI-IA. Behav Res Ther. 1999;37(2):183&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9990749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0005-7967(98)00087-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motlagh H. Impact of Event Scale-revised. J Physiother. 2010;56(3):203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20795930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1836-9553(10)70029-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Iii CFR, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. 1989;28(2):193&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2748771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0165-1781(89)90047-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasreddine ZS, Phillips NA, B&#xe9;dirian V, Charbonneau S, Whitehead V, Collin I, et al. The Montreal Cognitive Assessment, MoCA: a brief screening tool for mild cognitive impairment. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2005;53(4):695&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.2005.53221.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demiry&#xfc;rek E, &#xc7;eki&#xe7; D, I&#x15f;sever K, Gen&#xe7; AC, Yaylaci S, Demiry&#xfc;rek BE. Depression and Anxiety Disorders in COVID-19 Survivors: Role of Inflammatory Predictors. Noro Psikiyatr Ars. 2022;59(2):105&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35685053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9142020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuch FB, Bulzing RA, Meyer J, Vancampfort D, Firth J, Stubbs B, et al. Associations of moderate to vigorous physical activity and sedentary behavior with depressive and anxiety symptoms in self-isolating people during the COVID-19 pandemic: A cross-sectional survey in Brazil. Psychiatry Res. 2020;292: 113339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32745795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7384423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sensoy B, Gunes A, Ari S. Anxiety and depression levels in Covid-19 disease and their relation to hypertension. Clin Exp Hypertens. 2021;43(3):237&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33176496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10641963.2020.1847132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadad R, Khoury J, Stanger C, Fisher T, Schneer S, Ben-Hayun R, et al. Cognitive dysfunction following COVID-19 infection. J Neurovirol. 2022;28(3):430&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35618983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9134977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13365-022-01079-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mone P, Pansini A, Frullone S, de Donato A, Buonincontri V, De Blasiis P, et al. Physical decline and cognitive impairment in frail hypertensive elders during COVID-19. Eur J Intern Med. 2022;99:89&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35300886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8919809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejim.2022.03.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa V, S&#xe1; M, Carlos RJ. Randomised controlled trial of a cognitive narrative intervention for complicated grief in widowhood. Aging Ment Health. 2014;18(3):354&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24073815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13607863.2013.833164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollayeva T, Thurairajah P, Burton K, Mollayeva S, Shapiro CM, Colantonio A. The Pittsburgh sleep quality index as a screening tool for sleep dysfunction in clinical and non-clinical samples: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Medicine Reviews. 2016:52&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu SA-OX, Luo Z, Liu H, Zhu J, Zhu Y, Hou D, et al. Multicentre, multitime, multidimension, prospective follow-up cohort study on patients during the first wave of COVID-19 in China: a study protocol. BMJ Open. 2025;15(1):e083023. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2023-083023 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herdman M, Gudex C, Lloyd A, Janssen M, Kind P, Parkin D, et al. Development and preliminary testing of the new five-level version of EQ-5D (EQ-5D-5L). Qual Life Res. 2011;20(10):1727&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21479777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3220807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-011-9903-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo N, Liu G, Li M, Guan H, Jin X, Rand-Hendriksen K. Estimating an EQ-5D-5L Value Set for China. Value Health. 2017;20(4):662&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28408009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jval.2016.11.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe4;uerle A, Steinbach J, Schweda A, Beckord J, Hetkamp M, Weism&#xfc;ller B, et al. Mental Health Burden of the COVID-19 Outbreak in Germany: Predictors of Mental Health Impairment. J Prim Care Community Health. 2020;11:2150132720953682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32865107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7457643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2150132720953682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen A, Selles RW, De Ridder WA, Ter Stege MHP, Souer JS, Wouters RM. What Is the Impact of the COVID-19 Pandemic on Quality of Life and Other Patient-reported Outcomes? An Analysis of the Hand-Wrist Study Cohort. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2021;479(2):335&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33044314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CORR.0000000000001514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ping W, Zheng J, Niu X, Guo C, Zhang J, Yang H, et al. Evaluation of health-related quality of life using EQ-5D in China during the COVID-19 pandemic. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(6): e0234850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32555642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7302485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0234850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballouz T, Menges D, Anagnostopoulos A, Domenghino A, Aschmann HE, Frei A, et al. Recovery and symptom trajectories up to two years after SARS-CoV-2 infection: population based, longitudinal cohort study. BMJ. 2023;381: e074425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37257891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10230608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2022-074425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Re&#x2019;em Y, et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38: 101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin S, Li Y, Wang L, Zhao X, Ma X, Gao GF. Assessment of vaccinations and breakthrough infections after adjustment of the dynamic zero-COVID-19 strategy in China: an online survey. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2023;12(2):2258232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37691586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10512888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/22221751.2023.2258232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corfield EC, Martin NG, Nyholt DR. Co-occurrence and symptomatology of fatigue and depression. Compr Psychiatry. 2016;71:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27567301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comppsych.2016.08.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dyk TR, Thompson RW, Nelson TD. Daily Bidirectional Relationships Between Sleep and Mental Health Symptoms in Youth With Emotional and Behavioral Problems. J Pediatr Psychol. 2016;41(9):983&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27189691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jpepsy/jsw040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Cheng S, Zhang Z, Wang C, Wang A, Zhu W. Related risk factors associated with post-stroke fatigue: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurol Sci. 2021;42(4):1463&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32813167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-020-04633-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dayapo&#x11f;lu N, Tan M. Evaluation of the effect of progressive relaxation exercises on fatigue and sleep quality in patients with multiple sclerosis. J Altern Complement Med. 2012;18(10):983&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22967281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3469207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/acm.2011.0390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutherland G, Andersen MB, Morris T. Relaxation and health-related quality of life in multiple sclerosis: the example of autogenic training. J Behav Med. 2005;28(3):249&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16015459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10865-005-4661-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buttery S, Philip KEJ, Williams P, Fallas A, West B, Cumella A, et al. Patient symptoms and experience following COVID-19: results from a UK-wide survey. BMJ Open Respir Res. 2021;8(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;vd&#xe9;n M, Fratiglioni L, Glymour MM, Lindenberger U, Tucker-Drob EM. Education and Cognitive Functioning Across the Life Span. Psychol Sci Public Interest. 2020;21(1):6&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32772803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7425377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1529100620920576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H, Lu S, Chen J, Wei N, Wang D, Lyu H, et al. The landscape of cognitive function in recovered COVID-19 patients. J Psychiatr Res. 2020;129:98&#x2013;102. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychires.2020.06.022 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2020.06.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32912598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7324344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo MA-O, Malsy J, P&#x623;&#x2567;ttgen J, Seddiq Zai S, Ufer F, Hadjilaou A, et al. Frequent neurocognitive deficits after recovery from mild COVID-19. Brain Commun. 2020;2(2):fcaa205. https://doi.org/10.1093/braincomms/fcaa205 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almeria M, Cejudo JC, Sotoca J, Deus J, Krupinski J. Cognitive profile following COVID-19 infection: Clinical predictors leading to neuropsychological impairment. Brain Behav Immun Health. 2020;9: 100163. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbih.2020.100163 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbih.2020.100163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33111132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7581383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartung TJ, Neumann C, Bahmer T, Chaplinskaya-Sobol I, Endres M, Geritz J, et al. Fatigue and cognitive impairment after COVID-19: A prospective multicentre study. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;53: 101651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36133318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9482331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2022.101651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik P, Patel K, Pinto C, Jaiswal R, Tirupathi R, Pillai S, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome (PCS) and health-related quality of life (HRQoL)-A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Virol. 2022;94(1):253&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34463956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.27309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q, Chi P, Zhang Y. Association Between Pandemic Fatigue and Subjective Well-Being: The Indirect Role of Emotional Distress and Moderating Role of Self-Compassion. Int J Public Health. 2023;68:1605552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37497123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10366363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/ijph.2023.1605552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>