<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40450342</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1742-4755</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>22</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Reproductive health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Reprod Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of a comprehensive two-year research capacity intervention with sexual and reproductive health researchers in Sub-Saharan Africa.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>94</StartPage><MedlinePgn>94</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12978-025-02047-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Research training in Sub-Saharan Africa is crucial for strengthening the capacity of healthcare professionals and researchers to address specific sexual and reproductive health (SRH) challenges within their communities. Interventions that enhance research capacity and foster a culture of innovation within existing structures offer a practical and economical strategy capable of addressing national and sub-national SRH needs. This study evaluated an intervention to enhance reproductive health research skills to assess research competence changes among participants.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A pre-post intervention design was employed. Pre- and post-program assessments were conducted using the Clinical Research Appraisal Inventory (CRAI)-12 scale to establish baseline and endline levels of research competence. Descriptive statistics, chi-squared and Kruskal Wallis tests were used to analyze data. Our data interpretation is guided by the Social Cognitive Career Theory.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Faculty members and clinicians from Uganda and Rwanda completed the intervention and 84 had complete baseline while 77 had complete endline data. Analyses revealed significant improvements in nearly every item on the CRAI-12 scale after the research training program, including increased Self-Efficacy in Designing and Collecting Data (Factor 1); Reporting, Interpreting and Presenting (Factor 2); Conceptualizing and Collaborating (Factor 3); Setting Expectations for Research Staff (part of Factor 4); Describing the Funding Process (Part of Factor 5); and Protecting Study Participants (Factor 6) (all p&#x2009;=&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). The only items that did not improve significantly were Confidence in Asking Staff to Leave the Project Team when Necessary (part of Factor 4) and Locating the Appropriate Grant Application Forms (part of Factor 5).We proposed a conceptual framework outlining the hypothesized pathways through which training and skill development influence research-related career planning and progression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The research training intervention effectively improved participants' research competence. These findings underscore the importance of structured research training programs in enhancing research skills. Future research should focus on longitudinal assessments to explore sustained changes and the enduring impact of self-efficacy, outcome expectations (anticipations about career-related consequences), and research-related career goals on career planning and skill development.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Buser</LastName><ForeName>Julie M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for International Reproductive Health Training (CIRHT), University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, 48105, USA. jbuser@umich.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Tengera</LastName><ForeName>Olive</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Rwanda, Kigali, Rwanda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Charley</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, 48105, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumakech</LastName><ForeName>Edward</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing and Midwifery, Lira University, Lira, Uganda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gray</LastName><ForeName>Rachel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for International Reproductive Health Training (CIRHT), University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, 48105, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mukeshimana</LastName><ForeName>Madeleine</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Rwanda, Kigali, Rwanda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaberuka</LastName><ForeName>Gerard</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Rwanda, Kigali, Rwanda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bazakare</LastName><ForeName>Marie Laetitia Ishimwe</ForeName><Initials>MLI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Rwanda, Kigali, Rwanda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayikoru</LastName><ForeName>Jackline</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Reproductive Health, Gulu University, Gulu, Uganda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ntasumbumuyange</LastName><ForeName>Diomede</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, University of Rwanda, Kigali, Rwanda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, College of Medicine and Health Science, School of Medicine and Pharmacy, University Teaching Hospital of Kigali, Kigali, Rwanda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Endale</LastName><ForeName>Tamrat</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for International Reproductive Health Training (CIRHT), University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, 48105, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pebolo</LastName><ForeName>Pebalo Francis</ForeName><Initials>PF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Reproductive Health, Gulu University, Gulu, Uganda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Auma</LastName><ForeName>Anna Grace</ForeName><Initials>AG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing and Midwifery, Lira University, Lira, Uganda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>August</LastName><ForeName>Ella</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, University of Michigan School of Public Health, Ann Arbor, MI, 48105, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PREPSS (Pre-Publication Support Service), University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, 48105, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Yolanda R</ForeName><Initials>YR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for International Reproductive Health Training (CIRHT), University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, 48105, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, 48105, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Reprod Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101224380</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1742-4755</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>In this study, we explored whether a unique training program in Sub-Saharan Africa could help faculty members and clinicians become better at scientific research. This training aimed to help faculty members and clinicians improve confidence and self-efficacy in performing meaningful research. To understand how much the training helped, we asked participants about their research skills before and after they completed the program. We used the Clinical Research Appraisal Inventory (CRAI) -12 scale to measure these changes. We compared their answers before and after the training. Our results showed that after the training, participants reported improvement in their research competence. These findings suggest that structured training programs may benefit faculty members and clinicians in Sub-Saharan Africa looking to improve their research skills. Individuals may be better equipped to contribute meaningfully to research by focusing on these areas. Further research could explore the long-term effects of such training programs and how they might work in other environments or with different groups of people.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical research appraisal inventory (CRAI) -12</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nursing and midwifery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">OBGYN</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pre-post assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Research competence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Research training intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sub-Saharan Africa</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training effectiveness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Women&#x2019;s health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethics approval: Institutional Review Board (IRB) exception approval was obtained prior to beginning the study from the University of Rwanda (CMHS/IRB/210/2022) and the University of Michigan (HUM00203642). IRB approval was obtained from Gulu and Lira Universities (GUREC-2022-252). Participants were assured of confidentiality and privacy was respected. No identifiable information was collected. Consent to participate: An online explanation in English of the purpose of the study was provided prior to the survey. Written consent was obtained in English for all settings. Three of the 94 participants in the training programs declined to provide consent to share survey data. Their responses were not included in the analysis. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40450342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12978-025-02047-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12978-025-02047-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Khisa AM, Wao H, Brizuela V, Compaor&#xe9; R, Baguiya A, L&#xf3;pez G&#xf3;mez A, et al. Embedding research capacity strengthening in multi-country studies in low-and middle-income countries: learnings from sexual and reproductive health research. Global Health Action. 2024;17(1):2338634. https://doi.org/10.1080/16549716.2024.2338634 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/16549716.2024.2338634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38607331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11018088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghaffar A, Zennaro LD, Tran N. The African health initiative&#x2019;s role in advancing the use of embedded implementation research for health systems strengthening. Glob Health Sci Pract. 2022;10(Supplement 1):e2200318. https://doi.org/10.9745/GHSP-D-22-00318 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9745/GHSP-D-22-00318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36109064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9476485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busse CE, Anderson EW, Endale T, Smith YR, Kaniecki M, Shannon C, et al. Strengthening research capacity: a systematic review of manuscript writing and publishing interventions for researchers in low-income and middle-income countries. BMJ Glob Health. 2022;7(2):e008059. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.srhc.2024.100980 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.srhc.2024.100980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35165096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8845213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mbaye R, Gebeyehu R, Hossmann S, Mbarga N, Bih-Neh E, Eteki L, et al. Who is telling the story? A systematic review of authorship for infectious disease research conducted in Africa, 1980&#x2013;2016. BMJ Glob Health. 2019;4(5):e001855. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjgh-2019-001855 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2019-001855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31750001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6830283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agyepong IA, Godt S, Sombie I, Binka C, Okine V, Ingabire MG. Strengthening capacities and resource allocation for co-production of health research in low and middle income countries. BMJ. 2021;n166. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n166 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dossou JP, Assarag B, Delamou A, Van Der Veken K, Belaid L, Ou&#xe9;draogo M, et al. Switching the Poles in sexual and reproductive health research: implementing a research capacity-strengthening network in West and North Africa. Reprod Health. 2016;13(1):91. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12978-016-0203-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12978-016-0203-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27502593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4977648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keita N, Uzochukwu B, Ky-Zerbo O, Sombi&#xe9; I, Lokossou V, Johnson E, et al. Strengthening equitable health systems in West Africa: the regional project on governance research for equity in health systems. Afr J Reprod Health. 2022;26(5):81&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.29063/ajrh2022/v26i5.9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29063/ajrh2022/v26i5.9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37585100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sow S, Izugbara C, Diarra K, Djiteye M, Keita AM, Haidara FC, et al. Strengthening local capacity for abortion-related research in contexts with highly restrictive abortion laws: the case of STARS in Mali. Afr J Reprod Health. 2022;26(12):110&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.29063/ajrh2022/v26i12s.12 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29063/ajrh2022/v26i12s.12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37585166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CIRHT. Center for International Reproductive Health Training &#x2013; Reproductive Health Professionals Changes Lives [Internet]. 2024. [cited 2024 May 10]. Available from: https://cirht.med.umich.edu/ .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaba M, Birhanu Z, Fernandez Villalobos NV, Osorio L, Echavarria MI, Berhe DF, et al. Health research mentorship in low- and middle-income countries: a scoping review. JBI Evid Synthesis. 2023;21(10):1912&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.11124/JBIES-22-00260 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11124/JBIES-22-00260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lent RW, Brown SD. Social cognitive career theory at 25: empirical status of the interest, choice, and performance models. J Vocat Behav. 2019;115:103316. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jvb.2019.06.004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jvb.2019.06.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lent RW, Brown SD, Hackett G. Toward a unifying social cognitive theory of career and academic interest, choice, and performance. J Vocat Behav. 1994;45(1):79&#x2013;122. https://doi.org/10.1006/jvbe.1994.1027 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/jvbe.1994.1027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Liu X, Deng H. The perspectives of social cognitive career theory approach in current times. Front Psychol. 2022;13:1023994. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2022.1023994 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2022.1023994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36533045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9749854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Social foundations of thought and action: a social cognitive theory [Internet]. Englewood, Cliffs NJ. Prentice-Hall; 1986. 617 p. (Prentice-Hall series in social learning theory). [cited 2024 May 9] Available from: http://catalog.hathitrust.org/api/volumes/oclc/12080269.html .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolis J, May-Varas S, Mead T. Educational Learning Theories: 3rd Edition [Internet]. Education Open Textbooks; 2022. [cited 2024 May 9] Available from: https://openoregon.pressbooks.pub/educationallearningtheories3rd/front-matter/introduction/ .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullikin EA, Bakken LL, Betz NE. Assessing research Self-Efficacy in Physician-Scientists: the clinical research appraisal inventory. J Career Assess. 2007;15(3):367&#x2013;87. https://doi.org/10.1177/1069072707301232 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1069072707301232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buser JM, August E, Jacobson-Davies FE, Bongomin F, Kumakech E, Gray R, et al. Partnering to improve mentorship capacity for Ugandan reproductive health researchers: program description and evaluation. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2024;110(1):188&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.23-0459 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.23-0459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37983934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buser JM, Bazakare MLI, Kaberuka G, August E, Mukeshimana M, Gray R, et al. Strengthening healthcare delivery in Rwanda: implementation science training for reproductive health researchers. Sex Reprod Healthc. 2024;40:100980. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.srhc.2024.100980 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.srhc.2024.100980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38733830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busse C, August E. Addressing power imbalances in global health: Pre-Publication support services (PREPSS) for authors in low-income and middle-income countries. BMJ Glob Health. 2020;5(2):e002323. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjgh-2020-002323 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2020-002323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32133202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7042593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson GFWB, Switzer GE, Cohen ED, Primack BA, Kapoor WN, Seltzer DL, et al. A shortened version of the clinical research appraisal inventory: CRAI-12. Acad Med. 2013;88(9):1340&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.1097/ACM.0b013e31829e75e5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ACM.0b013e31829e75e5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23886999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3758379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrotta C, Downey V, Elabbasy D, Ingram C, Lo C, Naseer A, et al. Remote training for strengthening capacity in sexual and reproductive health and rights research: a systematic review. BMC Public Health. 2023;23(1):1964. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-023-16851-w .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-023-16851-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37817136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10566165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed Y, Taha MH, Khayal S. Integrating research and teaching in medical education: challenges, strategies, and implications for healthcare. J Adv Med Educ Prof. 2024;12(1):1&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.30476/JAMP.2023.99751.1854 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30476/JAMP.2023.99751.1854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38313425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10837463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akinyemi A, Fatusi A, Agunbiade O, Oyedun O, Ogunoye O, Stillman M, et al. Co-creation strategies for identifying abortion research gaps in Nigeria towards research capacity strengthening for early to midcareer abortion researchers. Afr J Reprod Health. 2024;28(3s). https://doi.org/10.29063/ajrh2024/v28i3s.2 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett S, Paina L, Ssengooba F, Waswa D, M&#x2032;Imunya J. Mentorship in African health research training programs: an exploratory study of Fogarty international center programs in Kenya and Uganda. Educ Health. 2013;26(3):183. https://doi.org/10.4103/1357-6283.126001 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1357-6283.126001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witteman HO, Hendricks M, Straus S, Tannenbaum C. Are gender gaps due to evaluations of the applicant or the science? A natural experiment at a National funding agency. Lancet. 2019;393(10171):531&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(18)32611-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)32611-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30739688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalaghonia N, Kwamie A. Making progress in early-career publishing: evolutions of the women&#x2019;s publication mentorship programme. Health Policy Plann. 2023;38(Supplement2):ii72&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1093/heapol/czad047 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapol/czad047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anjum G, Aziz M. Advancing equity in cross-cultural psychology: embracing diverse epistemologies and fostering collaborative practices. Front Psychol [Internet]. 2024 Apr 4 [cited 2025 Jan 16];15. Available from: https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/psychology/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1368663/full .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Belle S, Boydell V, George AS, Brinkerhoff DW, Khosla R. Broadening Understanding of accountability ecosystems in sexual and reproductive health and rights: A systematic review. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(5):e0196788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0196788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29851951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5978882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>