<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40450352</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2473-4209</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical physics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Phys</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Accelerated proton resonance frequency-based magnetic resonance thermometry by optimized deep learning method.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mp.17909</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Proton resonance frequency (PRF)-based magnetic resonance (MR) thermometry plays a critical role in thermal ablation therapies through focused ultrasound (FUS). For clinical applications, accurate and rapid temperature feedback is essential to ensure both the safety and effectiveness of these treatments.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This work aims to improve temporal resolution in dynamic MR temperature map reconstructions using an enhanced deep-learning method, thereby supporting the real-time monitoring required for effective FUS treatments.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Five classical neural network architectures-cascade net, complex-valued U-Net, shift window transformer for MRI, real-valued U-Net, and U-Net with residual blocks-along with training-optimized methods were applied to reconstruct temperature maps from 2-fold and 4-fold undersampled k-space data. The training enhancements included pre-training/training-phase data augmentations, knowledge distillation, and a novel amplitude-phase decoupling loss function. Phantom and ex vivo tissue heating experiments were conducted using a FUS transducer. Ground truth was the complex MR images with accurate temperature changes, and datasets were manually undersampled to simulate such acceleration here. Separate testing datasets were used to evaluate real-time performance and temperature accuracy. Furthermore, our proposed deep learning-based rapid reconstruction approach was validated on a clinical dataset obtained from patients with uterine fibroids, demonstrating its clinical applicability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Acceleration factors of 1.9 and 3.7 were achieved for 2&#xd7; and 4&#xd7; k-space under samplings, respectively. The deep learning-based reconstruction using ResUNet incorporating the four optimizations, showed superior performance. For 2-fold acceleration, the RMSE of temperature map patches were 0.89&#xb0;C and 1.15&#xb0;C for the phantom and ex vivo testing datasets, respectively. The DICE coefficient for the 43&#xb0;C isotherm-enclosed regions was 0.81, and the Bland-Altman analysis indicated a bias of -0.25&#xb0;C with limits of agreement of&#xa0;&#xb1;2.16&#xb0;C. In the 4-fold under-sampling case, these evaluation metrics showed approximately a 10% reduction in accuracy. Additionally, the DICE coefficient measuring the overlap between the reconstructed temperature maps (using the optimized ResUNet) and the ground truth, specifically in regions where the temperature exceeded the 43&#xb0;C threshold, were 0.77 and 0.74 for the 2&#xd7; and 4&#xd7; under-sampling scenarios, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study demonstrates that deep learning-based reconstruction significantly enhances the accuracy and efficiency of MR thermometry, particularly in the context of FUS-based clinical treatments for uterine fibroids. This approach could also be extended to other applications such as essential tremor and prostate cancer treatments where MRI-guided FUS plays a critical role.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 American Association of Physicists in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Sijie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Instrument Institute, School of Biomedical Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zong</LastName><ForeName>Shenyan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Science and Technology for Brain-Inspired Intelligence, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mei</LastName><ForeName>Chang-Sheng</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Harvard Medical School, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics, Soochow University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Guofeng</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Instrument Institute, School of Biomedical Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Yueran</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Instrument Institute, School of Biomedical Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>He</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Science and Technology for Brain-Inspired Intelligence, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Shanghai Fourth People's Hospital Affiliated to Tongji University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. 2022YFC2406900</GrantID><Agency>National Key Research and Development Program of the Ministry of Science and Technology of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No.82271956</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>81727806</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>11774231</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 23TS1400500</GrantID><Agency>Shanghai Municipal Science and Technology Explorer Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 2018SHZDZX01</GrantID><Agency>Shanghai Municipal Science and Technology Major Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 202402AA310071</GrantID><Agency>Major Science and Technology Program of Yunnan Province in Key Fields</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Phys</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0425746</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0094-2405</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fast reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">magnetic resonance thermometry</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40450352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mp.17909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Hynynen K. MRI&#x2010;guided focused ultrasound treatments. Ultrasonics. 2010;50(2):221&#x2010;229. doi:10.1016/j.ultras.2009.08.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winter L, Oberacker E, Paul K, et&#xa0;al. Magnetic resonance thermometry: methodology, pitfalls and practical solutions. Int J Hyperthermia. 2016;32(1):63&#x2010;75. doi:10.3109/02656736.2015.1108462</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rieke V, Butts Pauly K. MR thermometry. Magn Reson Imaging. 2008;27(2):376&#x2010;390. doi:10.1002/jmri.21265</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hesley GK, Gorny KR, Woodrum DA. MR&#x2010;guided focused ultrasound for the treatment of uterine fibroids. Cardiovasc Intervent Radiol. 2013;36(1):5&#x2010;13. doi:10.1007/s00270&#x2010;012&#x2010;0367&#x2010;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duc NM, Keserci B. Review of influential clinical factors in reducing the risk of unsuccessful MRI&#x2010;guided HIFU treatment outcome of uterine fibroids. Diagn Interv Radiol. 2018;24(5):283&#x2010;291. doi:10.5152/dir.2018.18111</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei C&#x2010;S, Panych LP, Yuan J, et&#xa0;al. Combining two&#x2010;dimensional spatially selective RF excitation, parallel imaging, and UNFOLD for accelerated MR thermometry imaging. Magn Reson Med. 2011;66(1):112&#x2010;122. doi:10.1002/mrm.22788</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimron E, Grissom W, Azhari H. Temporal differences (TED) compressed sensing: a method for fast MRgHIFU temperature imaging. NMR Biomed. 2020;33(9):e4352. doi:10.1002/nbm.4352</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Z, Gore JC, Grissom WA. Low&#x2010;rank plus sparse compressed sensing for accelerated proton resonance frequency shift MR temperature imaging. Magn Reson Med. 2019;81(6):3555&#x2010;3566. doi:10.1002/mrm.27666</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan J, Mei C&#x2010;S, Madore B, McDannold NJ, Panych LP. Fast fat&#x2010;suppressed reduced field&#x2010;of&#x2010;view temperature mapping using 2DRF excitation pulses. J Magn Reson. 2011;210(1):38&#x2010;43. doi:10.1016/j.jmr.2011.02.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Od&#xe9;en H, Todd N, Diakite M, Minalga E, Payne A, Parker DL. Sampling strategies for subsampled segmented EPI PRF thermometry in MR guided high intensity focused ultrasound. Med Phys. 2014;41(9):092301. doi:10.1118/1.4892171</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonathan SV, Grissom WA. Volumetric MRI thermometry using a three&#x2010;dimensional stack&#x2010;of&#x2010;stars echo&#x2010;planar imaging pulse sequence. Magn Reson Med. 2018;79(4):2003&#x2010;2013. doi:10.1002/mrm.26862</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim K, Diederich C, Narsinh K, Ozhinsky E. Motion&#x2010;robust, multi&#x2010;slice, real&#x2010;time MR thermometry for MR&#x2010;guided thermal therapy in abdominal organs. Int J Hyperthermia. 2023;40(1):2151649. doi:10.1080/02656736.2022.2151649</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaur P, Grissom WA. Accelerated MRI thermometry by direct estimation of temperature from undersampled k&#x2010;space data. Magn Reson Med. 2015;73(5):1914&#x2010;1925. doi:10.1002/mrm.25327</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poorter JD, Wagter CD, Deene YD, Thomsen C, St&#xe5;hlberg F, Achten E. Noninvasive MRI thermometry with the proton resonance frequency (PRF) method: in vivo results in human muscle. Magn Reson Med. 1995;33(1):74&#x2010;81. doi:10.1002/mrm.1910330111</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alimisis P, Mademlis I, Radoglou&#x2010;Grammatikis P, Sarigiannidis P, Th Papadopoulos G. Advances in diffusion models for image data augmentation: a review of methods, models, evaluation metrics and future research directions. arXiv. 2024. doi:10.48550/ARXIV.2407.04103</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Yu X, Stone L. Effective augmentation of complex networks. Sci Rep. 2016;6(1):25627. doi:10.1038/srep25627</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin D, Bu JJ, Liu Z, et&#xa0;al. Efficient medical image segmentation based on knowledge distillation. IEEE Trans Med Imaging. 2021;40(12):3820&#x2010;3831. doi:10.1109/TMI.2021.3098703</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlemper J, Caballero J, Hajnal JV, Price AN, Rueckert D. A deep cascade of convolutional neural networks for dynamic MR image reconstruction. IEEE Trans Med Imaging. 2018;37(2):491&#x2010;503. doi:10.1109/TMI.2017.2760978</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronneberger O, Fischer P, Brox T. U&#x2010;Net: convolutional networks for biomedical image segmentation. In: Navab N, Hornegger J, Wells W M, and Frangi A F, eds. Medical Image Computing and Computer&#x2010;Assisted Intervention&#x2014;MICCAI 2015; in Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Springer International Publishing; 2015:234&#x2010;241. doi:10.1007/978&#x2010;3&#x2010;319&#x2010;24574&#x2010;4_28</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dedmari MA, Conjeti S, Estrada S, Ehses P, St&#xf6;cker T, Reuter M. Complex Fully Convolutional Neural Networks for MR Image Reconstruction. In: Knoll F, Maier A, and Rueckert D, eds. Machine Learning for Medical Image Reconstruction; in Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Springer International Publishing; 2018:30&#x2010;38. doi:10.1007/978&#x2010;3&#x2010;030&#x2010;00129&#x2010;2_4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee C, Hasegawa H, Gao S. Complex&#x2010;valued neural networks: a comprehensive survey. IEEE/CAA J Autom Sinica. 2022;9(8):1406&#x2010;1426. doi:10.1109/JAS.2022.105743</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Fang Y, Wu Y, et&#xa0;al. Swin transformer for fast MRI. Neurocomputing. 2022;493:281&#x2010;304. doi:10.1016/j.neucom.2022.04.051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekanayake M, Pawar K, Harandi M, Egan G, Chen Z. Multi&#x2010;branch cascaded swin transformers with attention to k&#x2010;space sampling pattern for accelerated MRI reconstruction. arXiv. 2022. doi:10.48550/ARXIV.2207.08412</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding PLK, Li Z, Zhou Y, Li B. Deep residual dense U&#x2010;Net for resolution enhancement in accelerated MRI acquisition. arXiv. 2020. doi:10.48550/ARXIV.2001.04488</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddique N, Paheding S, Elkin CP, Devabhaktuni V. U&#x2010;net and its variants for medical image segmentation: a review of theory and applications. IEEE Access. 2021;9:82031&#x2010;82057. doi:10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3086020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal A, Rathi Y. A review and experimental evaluation of deep learning methods for MRI reconstruction. arXiv. 2021. doi:10.48550/ARXIV.2109.08618</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zbontar J, Knoll F, Sriram A, et&#xa0;al. fastMRI: an open dataset and benchmarks for accelerated MRI. arXiv. 2018. doi:10.48550/ARXIV.1811.08839</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kebaili A, Lapuyade&#x2010;Lahorgue J, Ruan S. Deep learning approaches for data augmentation in medical imaging: a review. J Imaging. 2023;9(4):81. doi:10.3390/jimaging9040081</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trabucco B, Doherty K, Gurinas M, Salakhutdinov R. Effective data augmentation with diffusion models. arXiv. 2023. doi:10.48550/ARXIV.2302.07944</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho J, Jain A, Abbeel P. Denoising diffusion probabilistic models. arXiv. 2020. doi:10.48550/ARXIV.2006.11239</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinton G, Vinyals O, Dean J. Distilling the knowledge in a neural network. arXiv. 2015. doi:10.48550/ARXIV.1503.02531</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan Y, Lyu J. Semi&#x2010;supervised distillation learning based on swin transformer for MRI reconstruction. In: Yu S, Zhang Z, Yuen P C, Han J, Tan T, Guo Y, Lai J, and Zhang J, eds. Pattern Recognition and Computer Vision; in Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Springer Nature Switzerland; 2022:67&#x2010;76. doi:10.1007/978&#x2010;3&#x2010;031&#x2010;18910&#x2010;4_6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murugesan B, Vijayarangan S, Sarveswaran K, Ram K, Sivaprakasam M. KD&#x2010;MRI: a knowledge distillation framework for image reconstruction and image restoration in MRI workflow. arXiv. 2020 doi:10.48550/ARXIV.2004.05319</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee D, Yoo J, Tak S, Ye JC. Deep residual learning for accelerated MRI using magnitude and phase networks. IEEE Trans Biomed Eng. 2018;65(9):1985&#x2010;1995. doi:10.1109/TBME.2018.2821699</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole E, Cheng J, Pauly J, Vasanawala S. Analysis of deep complex&#x2010;valued convolutional neural networks for MRI reconstruction and phase&#x2010;focused applications. Magn Reson Med. 2021;86(2):1093&#x2010;1109. doi:10.1002/mrm.28733</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Plumbley MD, Wang W. Weighted magnitude&#x2010;phase loss for speech dereverberation. ICASSP 2021 &#x2010; 2021 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP), Toronto, ON, Canada: IEEE, 2021:5794&#x2010;5798. doi:10.1109/ICASSP39728.2021.9414929</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tejani AS, Klontzas ME, Gatti AA, et&#xa0;al. Checklist for artificial intelligence in medical imaging (CLAIM): 2024 Update. Radiol Artif Intell. 2024;6(4):e240300. doi:10.1148/ryai.240300</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zong S, Shen G, Mei C. Proton resonance frequency&#x2010;based thermometry for aqueous and adipose tissues. Med Phys. 2021;48(10):5651&#x2010;5660. doi:10.1002/mp.15203</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zong S, Shen G, Mei C, Madore B. Improved PRF&#x2010;based MR thermometry using k&#x2010;space energy spectrum analysis. Magn Reson Med. 2020;84(6):3325&#x2010;3332. doi:10.1002/mrm.28341</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uecker M, Lai P, Murphy MJ, et&#xa0;al. ESPIRiT&#x2010;an eigenvalue approach to autocalibrating parallel MRI: where SENSE meets GRAPPA. Magn Reson Med. 2014;71(3):990&#x2010;1001. doi:10.1002/mrm.24751</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Kang Y, Yang J, He Y. A method to correct magnetic resonance imaging magnetic field drift. J Med Imaging Hlth Inform. 2018;8(7):1519&#x2010;1525. doi:10.1166/jmihi.2018.2465</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>