<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40450379</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1758-9193</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Alzheimer's research &amp; therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Alzheimers Res Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Deep-learning based multi-modal models for brain age, cognition and amyloid pathology prediction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>126</StartPage><MedlinePgn>126</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13195-025-01773-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), combined with artificial intelligence techniques, has improved our understanding of brain structural change and enabled the estimation of brain age. Neurodegenerative disorders, such as Alzheimer's disease (AD), have been linked to accelerated brain aging. In this study, we aimed to develop a deep-learning framework that processes and integrates MRI images to more accurately predict brain age, cognitive function, and amyloid pathology.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this study, we aimed to develop a deep-learning framework that processes and integrates MRI images to more accurately predict brain age, cognitive function, and amyloid pathology.We collected over 10,000 T1-weighted MRI scans from more than 7,000 individuals across six cohorts. We designed a multi-modal deep-learning framework that employs 3D convolutional neural networks to analyze MRI and additional neural networks to evaluate demographic data. Our initial model focused on predicting brain age, serving as a foundational model from which we developed separate models for cognition function and amyloid plaque prediction through transfer learning.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The brain age prediction model achieved the mean absolute error (MAE) for cognitive normal population in the ADNI (test) datasets of 3.302 years. The gap between predicted brain age and chronological age significantly increases while cognition declines. The cognition prediction model exhibited a root mean square error (RMSE) of 0.334 for the Clinical Dementia Rating (CDR) regression task, achieving an area under the curve (AUC) of approximately 0.95 in identifying ing dementia patients. Dementia related brain regions, such as the medial temporal lobe, were identified by our model. Finally, amyloid plaque prediction model was trained to predict amyloid plaque, and achieved an AUC about 0.8 for dementia patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These findings indicate that the present predictive models can identify subtle changes in brain structure, enabling precise estimates of brain age, cognitive status, and amyloid pathology. Such models could facilitate the use of MRI as a non-invasive diagnostic tool for neurodegenerative diseases, including AD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Chenxi</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of International Medical, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute on Aging and Brain Disorders, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurodegenerative Disorder Research Center, School of Life Sciences, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, Hefei National Laboratory for Physical Sciences at the Microscale, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Weiwei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of International Medical, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ni</LastName><ForeName>Ming</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Qiong</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute on Aging and Brain Disorders, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurodegenerative Disorder Research Center, School of Life Sciences, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, Hefei National Laboratory for Physical Sciences at the Microscale, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, Anhui, 230001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Linbin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute on Aging and Brain Disorders, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurodegenerative Disorder Research Center, School of Life Sciences, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, Hefei National Laboratory for Physical Sciences at the Microscale, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Mengguo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute on Aging and Brain Disorders, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurodegenerative Disorder Research Center, School of Life Sciences, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, Hefei National Laboratory for Physical Sciences at the Microscale, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China. yongshen@ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute on Aging and Brain Disorders, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China. yongshen@ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurodegenerative Disorder Research Center, School of Life Sciences, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, Hefei National Laboratory for Physical Sciences at the Microscale, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China. yongshen@ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Feng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China. fenggao7@ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute on Aging and Brain Disorders, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China. fenggao7@ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurodegenerative Disorder Research Center, School of Life Sciences, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, Hefei National Laboratory for Physical Sciences at the Microscale, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China. fenggao7@ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Alzheimers Res Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101511643</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alzheimer&#x2019; s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain aging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MRI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pattern recognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transfer learning</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted in accordance with the ethical standards of the Declaration of Helsinki and approved by the Medical Ethics Committee of the First Affiliated Hospital of the University of Science and Technology, China (Approval No. 2019 KY-26). All participants provided written informed consent prior to their inclusion in the study. The trial was registered at the Chinese Clinical Trial Registry (ChiCTR1900024777, http://www.chictr.org.cn/ ) on July 27, 2019. Consent for publication: Written informed consent for publication was obtained from all participants. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40450379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13195-025-01773-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13195-025-01773-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yamada M, Takechi H, Mori S, Aoyama T, Arai H. Global brain atrophy is associated with physical performance and the risk of falls in older adults with cognitive impairment. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2013;13(2):437&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1447-0594.2012.00927.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22935103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terry RD, Masliah E, Salmon DP, Butters N, DeTeresa R, Hill R, et al. Physical basis of cognitive alterations in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: synapse loss is the major correlate of cognitive impairment. Ann Neurol. 1991;30(4):572&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.410300410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1789684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardy JA, Higgins GA. Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: the amyloid cascade hypothesis. Science. 1992;256(5054):184&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1566067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1566067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long JM, Holtzman DM. Alzheimer disease: an update on pathobiology and treatment strategies. Cell. 2019;179:312&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2019.09.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31564456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6778042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jack CR Jr, Andrews JS, Beach TG, Buracchio T, Dunn B, Graf A, et al. Revised criteria for diagnosis and staging of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: Alzheimer&#x2019;s Association Workgroup. Alzheimers Dement. 2024;20:5143&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/alz.13859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38934362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11350039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson KA, Sperling RA, Gidicsin CM, Carmasin JS, Maye JE, Coleman RE, et al. Florbetapir (F18-AV-45) PET to assess amyloid burden in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease dementia, mild cognitive impairment, and normal aging. Alzheimers Dement. 2013;9(5 Suppl):S72-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23375563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camus V, Payoux P, Barr&#xe9; L, Desgranges B, Voisin T, Tauber C, et al. Using PET with 18F-AV-45 (florbetapir) to quantify brain amyloid load in a clinical environment. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2012;39(4):621&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-011-2021-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22252372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3315642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valizadeh SA, H&#xe4;nggi J, M&#xe9;rillat S, J&#xe4;ncke L. Age prediction on the basis of brain anatomical measures. Hum Brain Mapp. 2017;38(2):997&#x2013;1008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.23434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27807912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krizhevsky A, Sutskever I, Hinton GE. ImageNet classification with deep convolutional neural networks. Commun ACM. 2017;60:84&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3065386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashyam VM, Erus G, Doshi J, Habes M, Nasrallah IM, Truelove-Hill M, et al. MRI signatures of brain age and disease over the lifespan based on a deep brain network and 14 468 individuals worldwide. Brain. 2020;143:2312&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awaa160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32591831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7364766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Burkett BJ, Min H-K, Senjem ML, Lundt ES, Botha H, et al. Deep learning-based brain age prediction in normal aging and dementia. Nature Aging. 2022;2:412&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43587-022-00219-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37118071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10154042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lew CO, Zhou L, Mazurowski MA, Doraiswamy PM, Petrella JR. MRI-based deep learning assessment of amyloid, tau, and neurodegeneration biomarker status across the alzheimer disease spectrum. Radiology. 2023;309(1):e222441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.222441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37815445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller SG, Weiner MW, Thal LJ, Petersen RC, Jack CR, Jagust W, et al. Ways toward an early diagnosis in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: the Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease Neuroimaging Initiative (ADNI). Alzheimers Dement. 2005;1(1):55&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jalz.2005.06.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17476317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcus DS, Wang TH, Parker J, Csernansky JG, Morris JC, Buckner RL. Open Access Series of Imaging Studies (OASIS): Cross-sectional MRI Data in Young, Middle Aged, Nondemented, and Demented Older Adults. J Cogn Neurosci. 2007;19:1498&#x2013;507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1162/jocn.2007.19.9.1498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17714011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis KA, Bush AI, Darby D, De Fazio D, Foster J, Hudson P, et al. The Australian Imaging, Biomarkers and Lifestyle (AIBL) study of aging: methodology and baseline characteristics of 1112 individuals recruited for a longitudinal study of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Int Psychogeriatr. 2009;21(4):672&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1041610209009405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19470201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinton GE, Salakhutdinov RR. Reducing the dimensionality of data with neural networks. Science. 2006;313(5786):504&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1127647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16873662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dosovitskiy A, Beyer L, Kolesnikov A, Weissenborn D, Zhai X, Unterthiner T, et al. An image is worth 16x16 words: transformers for image recognition at scale. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He K, Zhang X, Ren S, Sun J. Deep residual learning for image recognition. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaswani A, Shazeer N, Parmar N, Uszkoreit J, Jones L, Gomez AN, et al. Attention is all you need. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulyanov D, Vedaldi A, Lempitsky V. Instance normalization: the missing ingredient for fast stylization. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioffe S, Szegedy C. Batch normalization: accelerating deep network training by reducing internal covariate shift. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loshchilov I, Hutter F. Decoupled weight decay regularization. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lecun Y, Bottou L, Bengio Y, Haffner P. Gradient-based learning applied to document recognition. Proc IEEE. 1998;86(11):2278&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/5.726791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang-Wai DF, Graff-Radford NR, Boeve BF, Dickson DW, Parisi JE, Crook R, et al. Clinical, genetic, and neuropathologic characteristics of posterior cortical atrophy. Neurology. 2004;63:1168&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.WNL.0000140289.18472.15</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15477533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duyckaerts C, Delatour B, Potier MC. Classification and basic pathology of Alzheimer disease. Acta Neuropathol. 2009;118:5&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-009-0532-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19381658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frederiksen KS. Corpus callosum in aging and dementia. Dan Med J. 2013;60:B4721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24083533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bousiges O, Blanc F. Biomarkers of dementia with lewy bodies: differential diagnostic with Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(12):6371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23126371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35742814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9223587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaroudi W, Garami J, Garrido S, Hornberger M, Keri S, Moustafa AA. Factors underlying cognitive decline in old age and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: the role of the hippocampus. Rev Neurosci. 2017;28:705&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/revneuro-2016-0086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28422707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J. Amygdala activity and amygdala-hippocampus connectivity: Metabolic diseases, dementia, and neuropsychiatric issues. Biomed Pharmacother. 2023;162:114647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2023.114647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37011482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Z, Hou Y, Xu C. Leucocyte telomere length, brain volume and risk of dementia: a prospective cohort study. Gen Psychiatr. 2023;36:e101120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gpsych-2023-101120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37705928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10496649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S L, W J. Florbetapir processing methods. Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease neuroimaging institute. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Burkett BJ, Min H-K, Senjem ML, Lundt ES, Botha H, et al. Deep learning-based brain age prediction in normal aging and dementia. Nature Aging. 2022;2:412&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43587-022-00219-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37118071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10154042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashyam VM, Erus G, Doshi J, Habes M, Nasrallah IM, Truelove-Hill M, et al. MRI signatures of brain age and disease over the lifespan based on a deep brain network and 14 468 individuals worldwide. Brain. 2020;143:2312&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awaa160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32591831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7364766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin SA, Townend FJ, Barkhof F, Cole JH. Interpretable machine learning for dementia: a systematic review. Alzheimers Dement. 2023;19(5):2135&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/alz.12948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36735865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng KP, Shen JY, Chiew HJ, Ng ASL, Kandiah N, Rosa-Neto P, et al. White matter hyperintensity as a vascular contribution to the AT(N) Framework. J Prev Alzheimers Dis. 2023;10:387&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14283/jpad.2023.53</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37357280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammitzb&#xf8;ll C, Dyrby TB, B&#xf6;rnsen L, Schreiber K, Ratzer R, Romme Christensen J, et al. NfL and GFAP in serum are associated with microstructural brain damage in progressive multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2023;77:104854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2023.104854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37418931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>